字幕来源：蓝光原盘   校对：阿九 仅供交流  严禁商用
片名：《桃色公寓》（又譯作：公寓春光）
On November 1, 1959, the population of New York City was 8,042, 783.
1959年11月1日，紐約市的人口達到了8,042,783.
If you laid them all end to end, figuring an average height of 5 feet 6?inches, ...
如果把所有的人頭尾相連按照每個人5英尺6英吋的話
.. they would reach from Times Square to the outskirts of Karachi, Pakistan.
這個長度可以從時代廣場一直連到巴基斯坦的卡拉奇的郊外
I know facts like this because I work for an insurance company, Consolidated Life.
我之所以很清楚這些事情，是因為我在一家名為聯合生活的保險公司工作
We're one of the top five companies in the country.
一家美國前五名的大公司之一
Our home office has 31,259 employees, ...
我們總部有31,259名員工
.. which is more than the entire population of, uh ... Natchez, Mississippi.
呃，大概比密西西比河岸的那其茲的總人數還要多
I work on the 19th floor. Ordinary Policy Department, ...
我在19樓工作，普通保單處理部
.. Premium Accounting Division, Section W, desk number 861.
保費清算分部w分區，桌號為861
My name is CC Baxter: C for Calvin, C for Clifford. But most people call me Bud.
我全名為CC·巴克斯特：C是卡爾文，C是克利夫德，但是人們一般都叫我巴德
I've worked here three years, ten months, and my take-home pay is $94. 70 a week.
我在這裏工作了三年零十個月，我扣稅後的實得工資是每周94.7美元
The hours in our department are 8.50 to 5.20.
我們部門的上班時間是從8:50到17:20.
They're staggered by floor so 16 elevators can handle the 31,259 employees ...
16部電梯來回在每層樓忙碌，這樣才能運送31,259名員工
.. without a serious traffic jam.
而不至於交通堵塞
As for myself, I very often stay on at the office and work for an extra hour or two, ...
對於我個人而言，我一般經常待在辦公室裏，有時候還會加班一兩個小時
.. especially when the weather is bad.
特別是天氣很差的時候
It's not that I'm overly ambitious. It's just a way of time ...
這不是因為我特別有野心，只是一種消磨時間的辦法
.. until it's all right for me to go home.
直到我回家時間的到來
You see, I have this little problem with my apartment.
你看，我的公寓有一點小問題
I live in the West 60s, just half a block from Central Park.
我住在西街60號，離中心公園只有半街之隔
My rent is $85 a month. It used to be $80 until last July ...
我的房租是每月85美元，去年七月份還是80美元
.. when Mrs Lieberman, the landlady, put in a second-hand air conditioner.
直到房東太太—利伯曼夫人安裝了一個二手空調後
It's a real nice apartment. Nothing fancy, but kind of cosy. Just right for a bachelor.
這確實是一間好公寓，樸實無華但還是很舒適，特別適合單身漢
The only problem is I can't always get in when I want to.
唯一的問題是我不能隨心所欲地隨時進去
Cut it out, Sylvia. We've gotta get out of here.
快停下來，塞爾維亞，我們要馬上出去
What's the panic? I'm gonna have another martini.
幹什麼這麼慌張呢？我還想喝一杯馬提尼
Please, Sylvia. It's a quarter of nine.
求你了，塞爾維亞，現在九點過一刻了
First you can't wait to get me here and then it's rush, rush, rush.
開始你讓我在這裏等，然後就一直匆匆忙忙
- Makes a person feel cheap. - Sweetie, it's not that.
- 讓我覺得自己是廉價的妓女 - 甜心，不是那樣的
But I promised the guy I'd be outta here by eight.
但我答應那傢伙8點整就出去的
- What guy? Whose apartment is this? - Some schnook that works in the office.
- 誰？這間公寓是誰的？ - 公司的某個傻鳥
- Good evening, Mr Baxter. - Mrs Lieberman.
- 晚上好，巴克斯特先生 - 利伯曼夫人，你好
Some weather we're having. Must be from all that meshugaas at Cape Canaveral.
這糟糕的鬼天氣一定是從好望角那裏傳過來
- You're locked out of your apartment? - No, no. Just waiting for a friend.
- 你被鎖在門外了嗎？ - 沒有，沒有，只是在等一個朋友
- Good night, Mrs Lieberman. - Good night, Mr Baxter.
- 晚安，利伯曼夫人 - 晚安，巴克斯特先生
- Where do you live? - I told you. With my mother.
- 你住在哪裏？ - 我告訴過你了，和我母親
- Where does she live? - 179th Street, in the Bronx.
- 她住在哪裏？ - 布朗克斯，179街
- All right. I'll take you to the subway. - Like hell you will! You'll buy me a cab.
- 好的，我送你到地鐵站 - 去死吧，你應該讓我打的回家
- Why do all you dames live in the Bronx? - You bring other girls up here?
- 為什麼你們這些小姐們都住在布魯克斯呢？ - 你還帶過其他的女孩到這裏？
Certainly not. I'm a happily married man.
當然沒有，我是一個快樂的已婚男人
- Hello there, Mrs Dreyfuss. - Something's the matter?
你好，爵弗斯太太有什麼問題嗎？
Uh, no. I... seem to have dropped my key. Ah, here it is.
哦，我好像把鑰匙放在…哈，在這裏
Such a racket I heard in your place.
我好像聽到你的房間很吵啊
Maybe you had burglars?
你房間是不是有小偷光顧？
Don't worry about that. There's nothing in here anybody'd wanna steal. Good night.
不要擔心這個，我的房間沒什麼好偷的，晚安
Sorry to bother you, Buddy-boy, but the little lady forgot her galoshes.
很抱歉打擾你，巴德小伙，但是開始那位小姐忘了她的手套
Mr Kirkeby, you were supposed to be outta here by eight.
科克比先生，你應該八點就離開的
I know, but those things don't always run on schedule like a Greyhound bus.
我知道，任何事情都不可能像公共汽車那麼準時的
I don't mind in the summer, but on a rainy night...
夏天還無所謂，但是在這樣的一個雨天
- I haven't had any dinner yet. - Sure, sure.
我還沒有吃晚飯呢，知道知道
Oh!
哦
I put in a good word for you with Sheldrake in Personnel.
我告訴你一個從人事部捨爾爵克先生那裏傳來的好消息
- Mr Sheldrake? - That's right.
捨爾爵克先生對
We discussed manpower promotionwise. I told him you're a bright boy.
我們討論了認識調動方面的問題，我告訴他你是非常合適的人選
They're always on the lookout for young executives. You're on your way up.
他們總是在尋找合適的年輕的經理，你馬上就可以被提升上去了
- And you're also out of liquor. - Mr Eichelberger, Mortgage and Loans,,, .
而且你的酒已經被喝光了，抵押和借貸部的愛其爾伯格先生
- .. last night he had a Halloween party. - Lay in some vodka and vermouth for me.
昨天晚上舉行了一個萬聖節晚會，給我留了一些伏特加和苦艾酒
- You still owe me for the last two bottles. - I'll pay you on Friday.
- 你還欠我兩瓶酒呢 - 我星期五付錢給你
Oh, and whatever happened to those little cheese crackers you used to have?
對了，你曾經用過的那個奶酪攪拌器怎麼了
Cheese crackers?
奶酪各攪拌器？
Cheers.
乾杯
- Good evening, Baxter. - Hi, Doc. Had a late call?
- 晚安，巴克斯特先生 - 嗨，醫生，看病這麼晚回來？
Yeah. Some clown at Schrafft's ate a club sandwich. - including the toothpick.
是的，一些小丑在斯科夫特吃三明治，總會把牙籤也吃了進去
- Well, good night, Doc. - Say, Baxter.
- 哦，晚安，醫生 - 回頭見，巴克斯特
The way you're beltin' that stuff, you must have cast-iron kidneys.
像你這樣天天折騰法，估計你有一個鐵打的腎
That's not me. Just once in a while I have a few people in for a drink.
那不是我，只是有時候一些朋友在我這裏喝酒
As a matter of fact, you must be an iron man all around.
事實上，你也確實很厲害，鐵人一個
From what I hear through the walls, you're at it every night.
每天從牆那邊都傳來那種聲音，看來你好像每天都在做愛
- I'm sorry if it gets noisy. - And sometimes there's a double-header.
不好意思吵這你們了，只是有時候我看連續兩場的棒球賽
- [tuts] A nebbish like you. - Yeah. Well, I'll see you, Doc.
像你一樣平凡好了，回頭見，醫生
You know, I'm doing some research at the Columbia Medical Center.
對了，你知道我在哥倫比亞醫學中心做研究
- Could you do us a favour? - Me?
- 你能幫我一個忙嗎？ - 我？
When you make out your will - and the way you're going, you should -
當你確立你的遺囑的時候在你上天國以後，你…
would you mind leaving your body to the university?
你介意把你的遺體捐贈給大學做研究嗎？
My body? I'm afraid you guys'd be disappointed. Good night, Doc.
我的身體？我恐怕你們要失望了。晚安，醫生
Slow down, kid.
慢走，孩子
Oh, for heaven ...
哦，在去天堂的路上…
From the world's greatest library of film classics, we proudly present...
來自世界最經典電影的收藏。我們榮譽推介…
.. Greta Garbo, John Barrymore, ...
…由格雷塔·卡潑，約翰·白瑞莫…
. Joan Crawford, Wallace Beery and Lionel Barrymore ...
…瓊·克若佛德，華萊士·比爾瑞和里昂內爾·白瑞莫…
.. in "Grand Hotel".
主演的"大旅館"。
But first, a word from our sponsor.
但是首先，請我們的贊助商致辭
If you smoke the modern way, don't be fooled by phoney filter claims.
如果你是時尚抽煙一族，不要被那些假冒的過濾嘴廣告所欺騙
And now, "Grand Hotel", ...
現在開始播放"大旅館"，
.. starring Greta Garbo, John Barrymore, ...
由由格雷塔·卡潑，約翰·白瑞莫…
. .Joan Crawford, Wallace Beery and Lionel Barrymore.
…瓊·克若佛德，華菜士·比爾瑞和里昂內爾·白瑞莫主演
But first, a word from our alternate sponsor.
但是首先，請我們的第二贊助商致辭
Friends, do you have wobbly dentures?
朋友們，你有搖動的假牙嗎？
- Hello. - Hiya, Buddy-boy.
喂，你好，巴德小伙
I'm in this bar on 61st Street and I figured I'd give you a little buzz.
我現在在61街的酒吧，於是我想給你掛個電話
That's very nice of you but ... who is this?
非常感謝，但是請問您是哪位？
Dobisch. Joe Dobisch, in Administration.
多比奇.行政部的喬·多比奇
- Oh, yeah. I didn't recognise your voice. - That's OK, Buddy-boy.
- 哦，我聽不出你的聲音 - 沒有問題，巴德
Like I was saying, I'm in this joint on 6ist and I think I got lucky.
- 我開始說過，我在61街口 - 我想我很幸運
I'm sorry, Mr Dobisch. I like to help you fellas out, but it's sort of late.
很抱歉，多比奇先生，我也很想幫你，可是現在太晚了
- Why don't we make it some other time? - Listen, kid. I can't pass this up.
- 我們改天再說好嗎？ - 聽著，小伙子，我這次控制不住
She looks like Marilyn Monroe.
她長得很像瑪麗蓮·夢露
I'm already in bed. And I took a sleeping pill. So I'm afraid the answer is no.
- 我已經上床睡覺了，還吃了安眠藥 - 我想給你的答案是不行
We're doing the monthly efficiency rating. I'm putting you in the top ten.
我們正在做月度績效評估，我把你放在前十位
You don't wanna louse yourself up, do you?
你不想浪費這一機會吧，不是嗎？
No. But how can I be efficient in the office if I don't get enough sleep at night?
不想，但是如果我晚上睡不夠的話，白天怎麼能高效呢
It's only eleven, and I just want the place for 45 minutes.
現在才11點，我只借用你的地方45分鐘
I'm getting lonely. Who are you talking to, anyway?
我好寂寞。你到底在和誰打電話？
- My mother. - Oh, that's sweet. That's real sweet.
- 我母親 - 哦，真是甜蜜，太幸福了
Ooh!
嗯！
Make it 30 minutes. What do you say, Bud, huh?
就是30分鐘，你說怎麼樣，巴德？
I'm all out of liquor, there's no clean glasses ...
我酒喝完了，而且還沒有乾淨的杯子
- There's no cheese crackers. No nothin'. - Let me worry about that.
- 沒有奶酪攪拌器，什麼都沒有 - 讓我來考慮這些事情吧！
Just leave the key under the mat and clear out.
你只要把鑰匙放在毯子下面，然後出去就行了
Yes, Mr Dobisch.
好吧，多比奇先生
Anything you say, Mr Dobisch[!]
你說什麼都行，多比奇先生
No trouble at ali, Mr Dobisch[!] Be my guest!
一點都不麻煩，多比奇先生，別客氣
We never close at Buddy-boy's.
巴德小伙子從來都不會讓我們失望的
"Looks like Marilyn Monroe"[!]
「長的像瑪麗蓮·夢露」！
- This the place? - Yeah.
就是這個地方嗎？是的
- How much? - 70 cents.
- 多少錢？ - 70美分
Get the money, will you?
幫我拿錢，好嗎？
Watch those stingers!
小心一點！
- Give him a buck. - Thanks, lady.
- 給他一美元 - 謝謝，小姐
Put it back, honey!
幫我再放回去，寶貝！
Attagirl.
太棒了
- Are you sure this is a good idea? - Can't think of a better one.
- 你認為這是一個好主意？ - 沒有比這更好的
Barging in on your mother so late at night.
這麼晚來打擾你媽媽方便嗎？
Don't worry about the old lady. One squawk from her and she's out of a job.
不要擔心老太太，只要他敢發出一聲抱怨，我就讓她失業
Get the key, will you?
幫我拿鑰匙，好嗎？
Not there! Under the mat.
不在那裏，在地毯下面
- Under the mat? - Yeah. Come on.
- 在地毯下面？ - 是的，快點
Open up. We haven't got all night.
把門打開，我們不能待整個晚上的。
- This is your mother's apartment? - That's right.
- 這是你母親的公寓嗎？ - 是的
Mildred! He's at it again!
米爾德爾德，他又在裏面做愛了！
- Morning, Mr Kirkeby. - How are you, Baxter?
- 早上好，克科比先生你好嗎？ - 巴克斯特先生
- They keeping you busy these days? - Yes, sir. They are indeed.
- 這幾天你是不是很忙？ - 是的，先生，確實很忙
Good morning, Mr Kessel, Miss Robinson, Mr Williams, Miss Livingston.
早上好，克塞爾先生，羅賓森小姐，威廉姆斯先生，李文斯頓小姐
Good morning, Mr McKeliway, Mrs Schubert, Mr Davis.
早上好，麥克維爾先生，斯庫布特夫人，戴維斯先生
Good morning, Mr Kirkeby. Good morning, Mr Baxter.
- 早上好，克科比先生 - 早上好，巴克斯特先生
- Morning, Miss Kubelik. - That's all. Take it away.
- 早上好，庫伯利克小姐 - 好了，準備出發
Watch the door, please. Blasting off.
請小心門口，馬上出發
- What did you do to your hair? - It made me nervous so I chopped it off.
- 你的頭髮怎麼這樣了？ - 讓我很不舒服，所以我絞短了它
- Big mistake, huh? - No. I sort of like it. [snuffles]
- 是不是覺得不太好？ - 不是，你這個髮型是我喜歡的那種
- You got a lulu. - Yeah. Better not get too close.
- 你很優秀 - 是的，最好不要靠太近
- I never catch colds. - Really?
- 我從來都沒有感冒 - 真的嗎？
I was reading some sickness and accident claims figures.
我讀過一些疾病和意外聲明數據
The average New Yorker aged between 20 and SO has two and a half colds a year.
平均20歲到50歲的紐約人每年都會得兩次半感冒
- That makes me feel just terrible. - Why?
- 這讓我感覺很恐怖 - 為什麼？
If I have no colds a year, some poor slob must have five colds a year.
如果我一年一次感冒都沒得，那一些可憐的傢伙不是要得五次感冒了
- Yeah. It's me. - You should a stayed in bed this morning.
- 是的，是我 - 你今天早上應該在床上休息的
I shoulda stayed in bed last night.
本來昨天晚上是應該睡覺的
19!
19樓！
Watch your step.
小心你的腳
- And watch your hands, Mr Kirkeby! - Pardon?
- 小心你的手，克科比先生 - 再說一遍？
One of these days I'm gonna shut these doors on you and ...
有一天我想用這門把你夾住
20 next!
下一站20層
That Kubelik. Boy, would I like to get her on a slow elevator to China!
那個庫伯利克小姐，小伙子，我想和她一起坐到中國的電梯
- She's the best operator in the building. - I'm pretty good myself.
她是這棟樓最漂亮的操作員，我也很優秀
- But she won't give me a date. - Maybe it's your approach.
但她從來都不和我約會，也許你能行
A lot of guys around here have tried all kinds of approaches. No dice.
她周圍很多人試過各種辦法，結果都不行
- What's she trying to prove? - She could just be a nice respectable girl.
- 她想要證明什麼？ - 她是一個很值得愛的女孩
Listen to him! Little Lord Fauntleroy.
聽他說過！小羅的佛特勞瑞
Hello. Mr Dobisch? This is Baxter on the 19th floor.
您好，多比奇先生，我是19層的巴克斯特先生
Oh, Buddy-boy!
哦，巴德小伙
I was just about to call you. I'm sorry about that mess on the living room wall.
我正想給你打電話呢！不好意思把你的臥室牆上弄得這麼髒
My friend kept insisting Picasso was a bum, so she started to do that mural.
我的朋友堅持認為畢加索是個遊民，於是她開始在牆上作壁畫
It's not Picasso I'm calling about.
我不是為了畢加索
It's the key to my apartment. You're supposed to leave it under the mat.
我來要我公寓的鑰匙，你說好要放在地毯下面
But I did. I distinctly remember putting it there.
我放了，我清清楚楚的記得放過了
Oh, I found the key all right. Only it's the wrong key!
哦，我也找到鑰匙，不過不是我的鑰匙
It is? No wonder I couldn't get into the executive washroom this morning.
是嗎？怪不得我今天早上進不了經理盥洗室
And I couldn't get into my apartment!
但是我卻進不了我的公寓
So at 4am I gotta wake up the landlady and give her a whole song and dance.
於是早上四點我叫醒房東太太，撒了很多不著邊際的謊言來騙她
That's a shame. I'll send the key right down.
不好意思我會派人送給你正確的房間鑰匙
And about your promotion.
關於你的提升報告
I'll send that efficiency report to Mr Sheldrake in Personnel.
我會把績效評估報告送給人事部的捨爾爵克先生
You may hear from him before the day's over.
你在今天之前應該可以聽到好消息
Thank you, Mr Dobisch.
謝謝，多比奇先生
From Mr Dobisch.
多比奇先生給你的
Wait.
等一下
For Mr Dobisch.
給多比奇先生的
Mm-hm. Mm-hm.
嗯哼，嗯哼
Vanderhof. Public Relations.
萬德豪夫，公共關係部
Oh, yes, Baxter. Just a minute.
哦，是巴克斯特，等我一下
All right, Miss Finch. Type up what we got so far.
好的，芬奇小姐把我們說好的這些打印好
Look, I've got you down for tonight, ...
看，原來我給你安排在今天晚上的
.. but I'll be using the place myself, so I'll have to cancel.
但是我今天晚上要自己用公寓，所以我必須取消你預定的時間
But it's her birthday. I already ordered the cake.
但是今天是她的生日，我已經定了蛋糕
But I am sick. I got a terrible cold and a fever. I got to go to bed right after work.
但是我病了，得了重感冒還發燒，我必須要在工作後回家睡覺
If you got a cold, you go to a Turkish bath. Spend the night. Sweat it out.
如果你得了感冒，你應該去泡一晚上土耳其浴，好好出出汗
That's how you get pneumonia. If I got pneumonia, I'd be in bed for a month.
那是你為什麼會得肺炎的原因。如果我得了肺炎，那我就要躺上一個月了
OK. You made your point. We'll just have to do it next Wednesday night.
好的，你說得有道理，我在下個星期三晚上可以嗎？
- It's the only night I can get away. - Wednesday, Wednesday ... Wednesday.
- 只有那天我才有空 - 星期三，星期三…星期三
I got somebody pencilled in.
已經有人預訂了
Let me see what I can do. I'll get back to you.
讓我來安排一下，我馬上給你回復
- Mr Eichelberger. - Oh, yes, Baxter. What's your problem?
- 愛奇爾伯格先生 - 哦，是巴克斯特，有什麼事情？
Wednesday is out? Oh, that throws a little monkey wrench into my agenda.
星期三不行？天啊，這把我的日程弄得一團糟
Thursday? No, I'm all tied up on Thursday.
星期四？不行，那一整天我都沒有空
Let's schedule that, uh ... meeting for Friday.
讓我來排排時間，呃，在星期五怎麼樣？
Friday.
星期五
Let me see what I can do. I'll get back to you.
讓我來盤算一下，等一下給你回復
Premiumwise and billingwise, we are 18 per cent ahead of last year Octoberwise.
在保險金和保單種類方面，我們比去年增長了18%
Hello? Yeah, Baxter. What's up?
喂？哦，巴克斯特，有什麼事情？
Instead of Friday, could you possibly switch to Thursday?
我把你的時間從星期五調到星期四如何？
You'd be doing me a great favour.
你幫了我一個大忙了
Let me check. I'll get back to you.
然我來看看，等下回復你
Consolidated Life. I'll connect you.
聯合生活，我以後聯繫你
Sylvia, it's for you.
塞爾維亞，你的電話
yeah?
喂？
Oh, hello.
你好
Sure I got home all right. You owe me 45 cents.
我當然自己回家了，你欠我45美分
Look, Sylvia. Instead of Friday, could we make it Thursday night?
聽著，塞爾維亞，不在星期五，我們星期四晚上如何？
Thursday?! Well, that's The Untouchables with Bob Stack!
星期四？！那好吧，那就取消和鮑勃·斯戴布的約會！
Bob who?
鮑勃是誰？
All right, so we'll watch it at the apartment. Big deal!
好的，那我們在公寓碰面，有什麼了不起！
Hello, Baxter? It's OK for Thursday.
喂，巴克斯特嗎？星期四可以了
Thank you, Mr Kirkeby.
謝謝，克科比先生
Mr Eichelberger, it's OK for Friday.
愛奇爾伯格先生，星期五可以了
Mr Vanderhof? OK for Wednesday.
萬德豪夫先生，星期三可以了
All right. I'll tell him.
好的，我會告訴他的
Hey, Baxter, that was Personnel. Mr Sheldrake's secretary.
嗨，巴克斯特，人事部捨爾爵克先生的秘書給你打了電話
She's been trying to reach you for the last 20 minutes. They want you upstairs.
她在開始的20分鐘裏一直想找你，他們讓你上樓
- Are you getting promoted? Or fired? - Would you care to make a small wager?
- 你要升職，還是被炒魷魚？ - 那我們來小賭一把如何？
- I've been here twice as long as you but... - Let's say a dollar?
- 我在這裏待的時間是你的兩倍，但是… - 賭一美元如何？
It's a bet!
賭就賭！
- Going up? - Oh! Excuse me.
- 上去嗎？ - 哦，對不起
27, please. Drive carefully. You're carrying precious cargo. I mean manpowerwise.
27樓，謝謝！小心一點，你在運送一件重要的貨物，也就是指大人物
27.
27樓.
You may not realise it, but I am in the top ten, efficiencywise, ...
看不出來吧，我是公司業績評估的前十名…
.. and this may be the day promotionwise.
今天我很有可能被提升
You're beginning to sound like Mr Kirkeby already.
你說話已經開始像克科比先生了
- Why not, as they're kicking me upstairs? - Couldn't happen to a nicer guy.
- 為什麼不呢，當他們把我送到樓上。 - 為什麼這種事情不能發生在一個好人身上呢
You know, you're the only one who takes his hat off in the elevator.
你知道，你是電梯裏唯一脫帽的人
Something happens to men in elevators.
這是電梯裏男人們的事情
It's the change of altitude. The blood rushes to their head.
這是地位改變的緣故，血都衝到他們的頭上了
- I could tell you stories ... - I'd love to hear 'em.
- 我可以給你講一些故事 - 我很樂意聽
We could have lunch in the cafeteria sometime.
我們什麼時候在外面吃頓飯如何
Or some evening, after work?
或者在工作後的某個晚上
-27.-0h.
- 27樓到 - 哦
- I hope everything goes all right. - I hope so.
- 我希望你一切順利 - 我也希望如此
They would call me today, what with my cold.
他們今天給我打電話，我的感冒也好些了
- How do I look? - Fine. Wait.
- 我看起來精神嗎？ - 很好，等一下
Thank you.
謝謝！
I noticed, when you were still on the local elevator, you always wore a flower.
我注意到了，當你在電梯上的時候，你總會戴一朵小花
Good luck. And wipe your nose.
祝你好運，把你的鼻子擦乾淨
CC Baxter, Ordinary Premium Accounting. Mr Sheldrake called me.
CC·巴克斯特，普通保費清算部，捨爾爵克先生叫我
I called you. That is, I tried to for 20 minutes.
我找你，而且我都找你20分鐘了
- I'm sorry. - Go on in.
- 不好意思 - 進去吧
- Baxter? - Yes, sir.
- 巴克斯特？ - 是的，先生
Come in, come in.
進來，進來
I was sort of wondering what you looked like, Baxter.
我正在想你長什麼樣子，巴克斯特
- Sit down. - Yes, Mr Sheldrake.
- 請坐 - 謝謝，捨爾爵克先生
Been hearing some nice things about you.
我聽說一些人都說你很優秀
Mr Dobisch says you're loyal, cooperative, resourceful.
克比奇先生說你忠誠，富有合作精神，很有潛力
- Mr Dobisch said that? - Mr Kirkeby tells me you often work late ...
- 他這麼說？ - 克科比先生說你經常加班
- .. without overtime. - You know how it is. Things pile up.
- 卻不領加班費 - 你知道的，事情總是一大堆
Mr Vanderhof in Public Relations and Mr Eichelberger in Mortgage and Loans ...
公共關係部的萬德豪夫先生，抵押和借貸部的愛奇爾伯格先生
.. would both like you transferred to their departments.
都希望你能調到他們的部門
Very flattering.
太過獎了
Tell me, Baxter. Just what is it that makes you so popular?
告訴我，巴克斯特，究竟是什麼原因讓你這麼受人歡迎？
- I don't know. - Think.
- 我不知道 - 想一想
- Would you mind repeating the question? - Look, Baxter. I'm not stupid.
- 你能在重複一下問題嗎？ - 聽著，巴克斯特，我並不傻
I know everything that goes on in this building every day of the year.
我知道這棟大樓每年每天發生的事情
You do?
真的嗎？
In 1957 we had an employee here, name of Fowler. He was very popular too.
1957年我們這裏有一個僱員，名叫弗勞爾，他也很受歡迎
It turned out he was running a bookie joint, ...
後來才知道他在開一個賭馬的投注點
.. tying up our switchboard, using our IBM machines to figure the odds.
連上我們的接線總機，並用我們的IBM計算機來計算冷門
The day before the Kentucky Derby I called in the vice squad, who raided him.
在肯塔基德比賽的前一天我告訴了刑警隊，他們逮捕了他
- The vice squad? - That's right.
- 刑警隊？ - 是的
What's that got to do with me? I'm not running any bookie joint.
這和我有什麼關係呢？我沒有開任何一個賭馬的投注點
- Just what kind of joint are you running? - Sir?
那你開的是哪種中介站呢？先生？
A key is floating around from Kirkeby to Vanderhof to Eichelberger to Dobisch.
一個聯結從克科比到萬德豪夫，到艾奇爾伯格，再到多比奇的關鍵東西
It's the key to a certain apartment.
這個東西好像是一間公寓
- Know who that apartment belongs to? - Who?
- 知道公寓是誰的嗎？ - 誰？
Loyal, resourceful, cooperative CC Baxter.
忠誠的，極具潛力和合作精神的CC·巴克斯特先生
- Oh. - Are you going to deny it?
- 哦 - 你打算否認這一切嗎？
No. I'm not going to deny it. If you'd just let me explain.
不，我不想否認這一切，如果你能給我一個解釋的機會
You'd better.
說吧！
Well, ...
好
.. about a year ago, I was going to night school, studying advanced accounting.
大約一年前，我正在上夜校，學習高級會計
One of the guys in our department - lives in Jersey - had to go to a banquet in town.
我們部門的一個住在澤西的傢伙，要參加鎮上的一個晚宴
He needed someplace to change into a tuxedo, so I gave him the key.
他需要一個地方來換燕尾服，於是我把鑰匙借給了他
Word must've gotten out because all sorts of guys were suddenly going to banquets.
這個消息一下全傳開了，忽然間所有人都要參加晚宴
You give the key to one guy, you can't say no to another. It all got out of hand.
你把鑰匙給了這個人，你就不能拒絕另外一個，事情終於無法控制
Baxter, an insurance company is founded on public trust.
巴克斯特，一個保險公司是建立在公眾信任之上的
Any employee who conducts himself in a manner unbecoming ...
一個僱員的行為如果不典的話
How many charter members are there in this little club?
你們這一個小團體有幾個人？
Just those four. Out of a total of 31,259.
只有四個，31,259人中的四個
So actually we can be very proud of our personnel ... percentagewise.
所以我們應該為我們的員工自豪，這個比例很小
That's not the point. Four rotten apples in a barrel, however large the barrel ...
但這不是重點，一個籃子中的四個爛蘋果，不管這個籃子有多大…
- Do you realise if this ever leaked out... - It won't!
- 你意識到這有多大的損害 - 不會的
Believe me. Never again. Nobody is gonna use my apartment from now on.
相信我，再也不會了，從現在開始沒有人會用我的鑰匙
- Where is your apartment? - West 67th Street.
- 你的公寓在哪裏？ - 西67街
You have no idea what I go through with the neighbours, the landlady and the key.
你不知道我是怎麼和鄰居和房東太太處理關於鑰匙的事情
How do you work it with the key?
你是怎麼把鑰匙給他們的？
I slip it to 'em in the office and they leave it under a mat. Never again. I promise.
我把鑰匙在辦公室的時候給他們，他們走的時候放在毯子下面，我保證再也不會了
- Yes, Miss Olsen? - Mrs Sheldrake, returning your call. On 2.
- 奧爾森小姐，有什麼事情？ - 捨爾爵克太太，在2線給你回電話.
[Sheldrake] Yes, dear. Where were you?
親愛的，你在哪裏呢？
You had to take Tommy to the dentist? No cavities? Good. Hold it, dear.
你應該帶托米看牙醫的？沒有蟲牙？好的，等一下，親愛的。
- Where are you going, Baxter? - I don't wanna intrude.
- 你去哪裏，巴克斯特先生？ - 我不想打擾你
- Since this is straightened out... - I'm not through with you yet.
- 既然事情已經清楚了 - 我和你還有事情
I won't be home for dinner tonight.
我今天晚上不能回家吃晚飯了
The branch manager from Kansas City is in town. I'm taking him to the theatre.
從堪薩斯來的分部經理今天在這裏，我要陪他去看戲
Music Man. What else?
劇名叫《音樂人》，還有什麼事情嗎？
No, don't wait up for me, darling. Goodbye.
不，不要等我，親愛的，再見
Tell me, Baxter. Have you seen Music Man?
告訴我，巴克斯特你看過《音樂人》這部戲嗎？
Not yet. I hear it's one swell show.
還沒有，不過聽說很不錯
How would you like to go tonight?
今天晚上你去怎麼樣？
You and me? I thought you were taking the branch manager from Kansas City.
你和我嗎？我想你要陪那位從堪薩斯來的經理吧！
No, I have other plans. You can have both tickets.
不，我有其他的事情，你可以把這兩張票都拿去
Well. .. that's very kind of you.
哦，你太好了
But I'm not feeling well. I've got this cold. I'm gonna go right home.
但是我今天身體不太舒服，感冒了，我只想馬上回家休息
Baxter, you're not reading me. I told you I have plans.
巴克斯特，你沒有弄懂我的意思，我告訴你有計劃的
So do I. I'm gonna take four aspirins, get into bed.
我也是，我就想吃四片阿斯匹林，然後上床睡覺
So give the tickets to somebody else.
那您把票給別人吧！
Look, Baxter. I'm not just giving these tickets. I wanna swap them.
聽著，巴克斯特，我不是想白給你票，我想和你交換
Swap 'em? For what?
交換？換什麼？
It also says here that you are alert, astute and quite imaginative.
他們還說你頭腦機敏，狡猾還非常有想像力
Oh?
哦？
Oh...
哦
That's good thinking, Baxter. There's gonna be a shift in personnel next month.
這就對了，巴克斯特，下個月人事部會有一個調動的機會
And as far as I'm concerned, you are executive material.
據我所知你是一個當經理的好材料
- I am? - Now put down the key.
- 我？ - 現在你把鑰匙留下
And put down the address.
寫好你的地址
It's on the second floor. There's no name over the door. It just says apartment 2A.
我的公寓在二樓，門上什麼都沒有，只寫著公寓2A。
- It's that cold. - Relax, Baxter.
很冷嗎？放鬆點，巴克斯特
Yes, thank you, sir.
好的，謝謝
You will be careful with the record player? Shh.
你們應該注意點唱片機，小聲點，否則鄰居會抱怨的
Oh, and about the liquor.
對了，還有酒的問題
I ordered some this morning. I don't know when they'll deliver it.
我今天上午已經預訂了，我不知道他們會什麼時候送過來
- This is going to be our little secret. - Of course.
- 這是我們的小秘密 - 當然
- You know how people talk. - Don't worry about that.
- 你知道人言可畏 - 不要擔心
- Not that I have anything to hide. - No! Anyway, it's none of my business.
- 我沒有什麼好隱藏的 - 是，總之，這不關我的事
Four apples, five apples. What's the difference?
4個人，5個人，有什麼區別呢？
Percentagewise.
很好的比率
Here you are, Baxter. Have a nice time.
給你，巴克斯特先生，玩得愉快
You too, sir.
你也一樣，先生
So I figure, a man in his position, he'll take me to EI Morocco, maybe 21.
我認為擔任像他這種職位的人，他會帶我去摩洛哥，可能是21。
Instead he takes me to Hamburger Heaven and some schnook's apartment.
結果他卻帶我去什麼漢堡天堂和一個傻瓜的公寓
- Good night. - Good night.
- 晚安
Oh! Miss Kubelik?
嘿，庫伯利克小姐
I've been waiting for you. I almost didn't recognise you.
我一直在等你，都差一點認不出你了
This is the first time I've seen you in civilian clothes.
這是第一次我看你穿便裝
- How'd it go on the 27th floor? - Great.
- 到27樓結果如何？ - 非常好
- Look, have you seen The Music Man? - No.
- 你看過《音樂人》嗎？ - 沒有
- Would you like to? - Sure.
- 那你想不想去看呢？ - 當然
We could get a bite to eat first, and then go.
我們可以先去吃點什麼然後再去看戲
- Oh, you mean tonight? - Yeah.
- 哦，你是說今晚嗎？ - 對啊！
- I'm sorry, I can't. I'm meeting somebody. - Oh.
- 不好意思，恐怕不行，我已經約了別人 - 太糟糕了
- You mean ... like a girlfriend? - No. Like a man.
- 你是指，和你的…你的女性朋友約會？ - 不，一個男的
I wasn't trying to be personal. The fellas in the office were wondering if you ever ...
我想這不是我個人的意見，公司的同事都在想你是否已經…
You tell 'em now and then.
你隨便什麼時候告訴他們
This date, is it... just a date? Or is it something serious?
這個約會…就是一個約會？有什麼很嚴重的問題嗎？
Well, it used to be serious. At least, I was. But he wasn't.
哦，曾經是一個很嚴重的問題，至少對我是的，但對他就不是
So now the whole thing's more or less kaput.
所以現在整件事情多多少少，意義都不大了
- In that case, couldn't you ... - I'm afraid not.
- 如果那樣的話，你能不能… - 恐怕不行
I promised I'd have a drink with him. He's been calling me all week.
我答應他和他喝酒的，他已經約我一個星期了
I understand.
我明白
Well, it was just an idea. I hate to see a theatre ticket go to waste.
哦，這只是我的建議，我不想看到這兩張戲票浪費
- What time does the show go on? - 8.30.
- 這場戲什麼時候開始？ - 20:30
Well, I could meet you at the theatre.
好吧，我盡可能到戲院找你
That's wonderful! It's the Majestic on 44th Street.
太好了，就在44街
I'll meet you in the lobby.
我在大堂等你
You know, I felt so lousy this morning. Had 101 fever.
你知道的，早上我的精神很差，好像得了101感冒
Now along comes my promotion and us - 11th row centre.
現在我得到了陞遷，並且還有11排中間的座位
And you said I should've stayed in bed.
你還說我要躺在床上休息
- How is your cold? - What cold?
- 你感冒怎樣了？ - 什麼感冒
After the show we could go out on the town. [hums dance tune]
看完戲我還能在鎮上到處逛逛
- I've been taking from Arthur Murray. - So I see.
- 我從亞瑟莫裏那裏得到了力量 - 我明白
There's a great band at EI Chico, in the Village.
在村上的EI奇科有一支很好的樂隊
- Around the corner from where you live. - Sounds good.
- 就在你家附近的拐口處 - 聽起來很不錯
- How do you know where I live? - Oh, I ... even know who you live with.
- 你怎麼知道我住在哪裏？ - 哦，…我甚至知道你和誰一起住
Your sister and brother-in-law.
你姐姐和姐夫
I know when you were born and where. I know all sorts of things about you.
我知道你什麼時候在哪裏生的，我知道所有關於你的事情
How come?
你怎麼知道這些的？
A couple of months ago I looked up your card in the group insurance file.
幾個月前在集團的人身保險裏，我看到了你的資料卡片
I know your height and your weight and your social security number.
我知道你的身高體重，你的社保號碼
You had mumps and measles and you had your appendix out.
你得過腮腺炎和麻疹，你的闌尾已經被割掉了
Don't mention the appendix to the fellas in the office.
不要給公司的那幫傢伙說我割了闌尾
I wouldn't want 'em to get the wrong idea about how you found out. Bye.
我不想讓人家在那裏亂猜：你是怎麼知道我割了闌尾？再見！
8.30!
20:30！
- Good evening, Mr Sheldrake. - Please, Fran. Not so loud.
- 晚上好，捨爾爵克先生 - 弗蘭，請不要這麼大聲
Still afraid someone might see us together?
你還害怕有人看到我們在一起？
- Let me take your coat. - No, Jeff. I can't stay very long.
- 我來幫你放大衣 - 不，傑夫，我不能待太久
- Can I have a frozen daiquiri? - It's on the way.
- 我能喝一杯冰凍的待克瑞雞尾酒嗎？ - 馬上就到
- I see you went ahead and cut your hair. - That's right.
- 我看到你走過來，而且頭髮已經剪短了 - 沒錯
- You know I liked it better long. - I know.
- 你知道我更喜歡你留長頭髮的 - 我知道
You want a lock to carry in your wallet?
你還想你的錢包有一個鎖呢！
- Evening, lady. Nice to see you again. - Thank you.
- 晚上好，女士，很高興再次看到你 - 謝謝
How long has it been, Fran? A month?
已經有多久了，弗蘭？一個月嗎？
Six weeks. But who's counting?
6個星期，那有什麼意義呢
I missed you.
我想你
Like old times.
老土
Same booth. Same song.
同樣的座位，同樣的音樂
- It's been hell. - Same sauce. Sweet-and-sour.
- 糟糕透了 - 同樣酸甜的沙司
You don't know what it's like, next to you in that elevator.
你不知道那是什麼感覺，在電梯裏與你隔肩而立
"Good morning, Miss Kubelik." "Good night, Mr Sheldrake."
「早上好，庫伯利克小姐。」「晚上好，捨爾爵克先生。」
I'm still crazy about you, Fran.
弗蘭，我對你仍是一往情深
Let's not start on that again, Jeff. Please? I'm just beginning to get over it.
- 傑夫，請不要開始就這樣說，好嗎？ - 我只是開始講述我對你的真情
I don't believe you.
鬼才信你
Look, Jeff. We had two wonderful months this summer.
聽者，傑夫，這個夏天的兩個月，我們過得很開心
But that was it. Happens all the time.
但是那都已經過去了
Wife and kids go away to the country and the boss has a fling with his secretary, ...
妻子和孩子一出國旅遊，老闆就可以和他的秘書…
.. or the manicurist, or the elevator girl.
…或者髮廊妹，或者電梯小姐偷歡.
Come September, the picnic's over. Goodbye.
九月份來到的時候，野餐結束了，也是說再見的時候了
The kids go back to school, the boss goes back to the wife, ...
子女們要重新回到學校，老闆也要回到他夫人的身邊…
.. and the girl ...
…至於那可憐的女孩
They don't make these shrimp like they used to.
他們再也不會像以往一樣，做她愛吃的龍蝦
I never said goodbye, Fran.
弗蘭，我從來都沒有說分手
For a while there, you try kidding yourself that you're going with an unmarried man.
有那麼一段時間，你開玩笑說，說你快樂得像一個單身漢
Then one day he keeps looking at his watch ...
然後，有一天他就開始不停地看表
.. and asks you if any lipstick's showing, ...
…並問我你身上是不是還有口紅的痕跡。
.. then rushes out to catch the 7.14 to White Plains.
…然後就衝出去，去趕開往白色平原的火車
So you fix yourself a cup of instant coffee ...
就像喝一杯速溶咖啡一樣瀟灑…
.. and you sit there by yourself and you think, ...
…你坐在那裏，然後在想…
.. and it all begins to look so ... ugly.
…一切看起來都是那麼的無聊.
How do you think I felt riding home on that 7.14 train?
你知道我趕19:14回家的火車是什麼感受嗎？
Why do you keep calling me, Jeff? What do you want from me?
傑夫，你為什麼還要給我打電話？你還要我怎麼樣？
I want you back, Fran.
弗蘭，我想你回到我身邊
Sorry, Mr Sheldrake. I'm full up. You'll have to take the next elevator.
不好意思，捨爾爵克先生，我現在很忙，你應該去找另外一個人去了
You're not giving me a chance, Fran. I have something to tell you.
弗蘭，你都不給我一個機會，我有一些事情要告訴你
- Go ahead. Tell me. - Not here. Can't we go someplace else?
- 快說啊，什麼事情 - 不在這裏，我們能換一個地方嗎？
- No. I have a date at 8.30. - Oh?
- 不行，我在8:30還有一個約會 - 什麼？
- Important? - Not very, but I'm gonna be there anyway.
- 很重要嗎？ - 不是，但是我不能爽約.
- You ready order dinner now? - No. No dinner.
- 你想現在吃東西嗎？ - 不，我不想吃
Just bring us two more drinks, will you?
再來兩杯，好嗎？
Fran, do you remember that last weekend we had?
弗蘭，你還記得我們在一起的那個週末嗎？
Do I! That leaky boat you rented, and me in a black negligee and a life preserver.
我記得！你租的那條破船，讓我穿著黑色的睡衣，還戴著救生圈
Do you remember what we talked about?
那你記得我們說過什麼嗎？
- We talked about a lot of things. - I mean about my getting a divorce.
- 我們說過的一些事情 - 我會離婚的。
We didn't talk about it, Jeff. You did.
我們沒有說過這個，傑夫。是你說的
You didn't believe me, did you?
你不相信我，是嗎？
They got it on a long-playing record now. "Music to String Her Along By."
他們現在換了一張唱片。「音樂把她帶到身邊。」
"My wife doesn't understand me. You're the best thing that ever happened to me."
「我妻子根本不理解我。你是我碰到的讓我最幸福的人」
- That's enough, Fran. - "Trust me, baby. We'll work it out."
- 這還不夠嘛？弗蘭。 - 「相信我，寶貝，一切都會好的。」
- You're not being funny. - I wasn't trying.
- 別開玩笑了 - 我沒有
- Fran, just listen to me for a minute. - All right. I'm sorry.
- 弗蘭，你就聽我講幾分鐘。 - 好吧。對不起。
I saw my lawyer this morning. I wanted his advice about the best way to handle it.
我今天早上去見律師了，向他問了些解決問題的方案。
- Handle what? - What do you think?
- 解決什麼問題？ - 你認為呢？
Let's get something straight, Jeff. I never asked you to leave your wife.
老實說，傑夫，我從來都沒有讓你離開你的妻子
Of course not. You had nothing to do with it.
當然沒有。你不要多想。
Are you sure that's what you want?
你確認你是認真的嗎？
I'm sure ... if you'll just tell me that you still love me.
當然…只要你說你還愛我
You know I do.
你知道我的心意
Fran.
弗蘭
Jeff, darling ...
傑夫，親愛的…
It is getting crowded. Let's get out of here.
這裏人太多了，我們出去吧！
Taxi!
出租車！
- Jeff, I have that date, remember? - But I love you, remember?
- 傑夫，我還有個約會，記得嗎？ - 但是我愛你，記得嗎？
- [whistles] - Where are we going?
我們去哪兒？
- Not back to that leaky boat? - I promise.
- 不會再去那條破船吧？ - 我保證不會。
51 West 67th.
西67街51號
Congratulations.
恭喜你
Would you mind? CC Baxter - that's me.
你在意嗎？CC·巴克斯特，是我。
Thank you.
謝謝
[Kirkeby] Hi, Buddy-boy. Congratulations and all that jazz.
嗨，巴德男孩，恭喜你，真讓人開心
- Hi, fellas. - Well, you made it, just like we promised.
嘿，好傢伙好了，你升職了，正如我們許諾的那樣
Quite an office. Name on the door, rug on the floor.
真漂亮的辦公室，看看門上的名字，地上的毯子
Teamwork: that's what counts in this organisation. All for one and one for all.
團隊工作：是一個組織存在的前提。人人為我，我為人人
- Know what I mean? - I have a vague idea.
- 知道我什麼意思嗎？ - 不太清楚
Baxter, we're a little disappointed in you, gratitudewise.
巴克斯特，我們對你有點失望，竟然一點感謝的表示都沒有
- Oh, I'm very grateful. - Then why are you locking us out?
- 哦，我非常感謝各位的幫助 - 那你為什麼把我們拒之門外呢？
Well, it's been sort of rough the past few weeks, what with my cold and ... like that.
哦，過去幾個星期裏對大家確有不周之處，那是因為我感冒了…
We went to bat for you. Now you won't play ball with us.
我們把你提上來，現在你卻不理我們了
After all, it's my apartment. It's private property, not a public playground.
說到底，這是我的公寓，我的私人財產，不是公眾的遊樂場
So you got yourself a girl. That's OK with us. But not every night in the week!
你是不是也找了一個女朋友？這沒有問題，你總不會每天晚上都做愛吧！
How selfish can you get?
你怎麼能這麼自私呢？
Last week I had to use my nephew's car and take Sylvia to a drive-in in Jersey.
上個星期我不得不借我侄子的汽車，帶著塞維利亞開車到澤西的汽車旅館
I'm too old for that sort of thing - I mean in a Volkswagen.
我太老了，不能那樣折騰，我是說在大眾汽車裏
I sympathise with you. Believe me, I'm very sorry.
我很同情你。相信我，我對此也非常的難過
- You'll be a lot sorrier. - Are you threatening me?
- 你會為此更後悔的。 - 你在威脅我嗎？
Listen, Baxter. We made you and we can break you.
聽著，巴克斯特，我們可以提你上來，也可以把你踢回原形
- Good morning, Mr Sheldrake. - Good morning, gentlemen.
- 早上好，捨爾爵克先生。 - 早上好，先生們
- Baxter, do you like your office? - Yes, sir. I wanna thank you very much.
- 巴克斯特，喜歡你的辦公室嗎？ - 是的，先生，非常感謝你的提攜
Don't thank me. Your friends here recommended you.
不要謝我，都是你這裏的朋友大力推薦你的
- We just dropped by to wish him luck. - We know you won't let us down.
我們順便過來來祝他好運，我們知道你不會讓我們失望的
So long, fellas. Drop in any time. The door is always open ... to my office.
再見，有空過來坐坐。我辦公室的大門…永遠對你們敞開
I like the way you handled that, Baxter.
我喜歡你處事的方式，巴克斯特先生
- How does it feel to be an executive? - Oh, fine.
- 做經理的感覺如何？ - 哦，很好
- I'll work hard to justify your confidence. - I'm sure you will.
- 我會努力工作來增強你對我的信心 - 我相信你會的
About the apartment. Now that you've got a raise, can't we afford a second key?
關於你公寓的事情，既然你已經提升了，我們能不能多配一把鑰匙
- I guess so. - You know my secretary, Miss Olsen?
- 我想沒問題的 - 你知道我的秘書，奧爾森小姐？
- Oh, yeah. Is she the lucky girl that ... ? - Oh, no, no.
- 哦，她也是你喜歡的人之一嗎？ - 哦，不不不
I just meant that she's kind of a busybody, and passing that key back and forth ...
我只是說她是那種喜歡多管閒事的人，把鑰匙遞來遞去的…
- Why take chances? - You can't be too careful.
- 萬一被她發現的話… - 你不用太謹慎了
Oh, I ... have something I think belongs to you.
對了，我想…我這裏可能有一些東西是你的
- Me? - I mean the young lady, whoever she is.
- 我的？ - 我是說那位年輕的女士，雖然我不知道她是誰
- I found it when I got back last night. - Oh. Thanks.
- 昨天晚上我回來的時候發現的 - 哦，謝謝
The mirror is broken. It was broken when I found it.
鏡子是破的。當我發現的時候就是破的
- Yeah. She threw it at me. - Sir?
- 哦，她用這鏡子砸了我。 - 沒事吧，先生？
You know how it is. They always give you a bad time.
你知道這是什麼回事的了，他們總不會讓你好過的
Yeah, I know how it is.
哦，我知道
You see a girl every week for laughs and they think you're gonna divorce your wife.
你每天對著一個女孩笑，他們就認為你要和你的妻子離婚
- Now I ask you, is that fair? - No, sir. It's very unfair.
- 我問你，這公平嗎？ - 不，非常不公平
- Especially to your wife. - Yeah.
特別是對你的妻子。是的
You know, Baxter, I envy you. A bachelor, all the dames you want, no complications.
你知道，巴克斯特，我很羨慕你，一個單身漢，想幹什麼，就幹什麼，無所顧忌
That's the life all right.
那才是真正的生活
- Put me down for Thursday again. - Roger.
- 我星期四還需要那公寓 - 明白
And I'll get that other key.
到時候我就用那把鑰匙
- Merry Christmas. I'll connect you. - Merry Christmas. Consolidated Life.
- 聖誕快樂，到時候再聯繫 - 聖誕快樂，聯合生活
Merry Christmas. I'm ringing.
聖誕快樂，我正在打電話
Yeah? Yeah?!
喂？喂？
Where?
哪裏？
You bet!
你猜！
Somebody watch my line. There's a swingin' party on the 19th floor!
有人佔住我的線路。19樓有一個晚會
Oh, what fun it is to ride in a one-horse open sleigh
我們滑雪多快樂，我們坐在雪橇上
Hey! Jingle bells, jingle bells, jingle all the way
嗨，叮叮噹，叮叮噹，鈴兒響叮噹
So I said to him "Never again. Either you get yourself a bigger car or a smaller girl."
於是我對他說：「去你的吧，要麼自己找輛大卡車要麼就換個小點兒的姑娘吧」
Miss Kubelik? Miss ...
庫伯利克小姐…
- Merry Christmas. - Thank you.
- 聖誕快樂 - 謝謝
- I thought you were avoiding me. - What gave you that idea?
- 我感覺你好像在躲著我 - 為什麼會這麼想呢？
In six weeks you've only been in my elevator once, and you kept on your hat.
在6個星期裏你只坐過一次我的電梯，而且還戴著帽子
As a matter of fact, I was rather hurt that night you stood me up.
事實上，那天晚上我等了很久，你都沒有到，這確實讓我很傷心
I don't blame you. It was unforgivable.
我知道，這的確不可原諒
- I forgive you. - You shouldn't.
- 我原諒你了 - 你不會的
You couldn't help it. You can't suddenly walk out on one man ...
這種事情你也沒有辦法的，你不可能突然對那個男人說…
.. because you have a date with another man.
因為我和另外一個男人還有一個約會
- You did the decent thing. - Don't be too sure.
- 你做得沒錯 - 不要太自信
Just because I wear a uniform, that doesn't make me a Girl Scout.
就是因為我穿的是制服，這並不能使我成為一個女童子軍
A second administrative assistant has to be a pretty good judge of character.
第二管理助理應該是一個非常好的職位
And as far as I'm concerned, you're tops.
而且據我所知，你非常優秀
I mean decencywise and ... otherwisewise.
我使說你非常的優雅，有氣質
Cheers.
乾杯
- One more. - I shouldn't drink while driving.
- 再來一杯 - 我操作電梯的時候不能喝酒
You're so right. By the power vested in me, I declare this elevator out of order.
你說得很對，憑借我的權利我宣佈這部電梯停止工作
Shall we join the natives?
我們去和他們一起狂歡嗎？
- Why not? They seem friendly enough. - Don't you believe it.
- 為什麼不呢，他們這麼的友好 - 你還不相信嗎？
There'll be human sacrifices. White-collar workers tossed into computers ...
這裏將有人作出犧牲…白領們將東西投進計算機
.. and punched full of little square holes.
打得全是小方孔
- How many drinks did you have? - Three!
- 你喝了幾杯了？ - 三杯
- I thought so. - Wait. I hear the sound of running water.
- 我想也是的 - 等一下，我聽到了流水聲
- I'll be right back! - I'll be right here.
- 我馬上就回來 - 我等你
[slurring] Hi!
嗨！
How's the branch manager from Kansas City?
你好，來自堪薩斯的分部經理？
- I beg your pardon? - I'm Miss Olsen.
- 對不起，請再說一遍 - 我是奧爾森小姐
Mr Sheldrake's secretary.
捨爾爵克先生的秘書
So you don't have to play innocent with me.
所以你不要在我面前裝無辜。
He used to tell his wife I was the branch manager from Seattle ...
他曾經告訴他妻子我是來自西雅圖的經理
.. four years ago when we were having a little ring-a-ding-ding.
四年前當我們在一起瘋狂的玩樂的時候…
- I don't know what you're talking about. - Before me it was Miss Rossi in Auditing.
- 我不知道你在說什麼 - 在我之前是審計部的羅斯小姐
And after me it was Miss Koch in Disability.
在我之後是死亡險部門的科奇小姐
And right before you was a Miss, um ...
在你之前也是一個小姐，呃…
Oh, what's her name? On the 25th floor.
哦，她叫什麼名字，在25樓工作
- Would you excuse me? - What for? You haven't done anything.
你應該說聲對不起？為什麼？你什麼都沒有做
It's him. Oh, what a salesman!
是他，哦，那個推銷員！
Always the last booth in the Chinese restaurant...
總是坐在那個中餐廳同樣的位子…
.. and the same pitch about divorcing his wife.
…又用同樣的借口和他妻子離婚
Then, in the end, you wind up with egg foo yung on your face.
然後，最後一切都雞飛蛋打
Miss Kubelik!
庫伯利克小姐
Well, thank you, Miss Olsen.
哦，謝謝你，奧爾森小姐
Always happy to do a little something for our girls in uniform.
非常樂意為我們的服務姑娘稍盡綿薄之力
Are you all right? What's the matter?
你還好嗎？出什麼事情了嗎？
Nothing. There are just too many people here.
沒有，只是這裏人太多了
Why don't we step into my office? There's something I want your opinion about.
為什麼不到我的辦公室坐坐呢？有些事情我想徵求你的意見
I have my own office now. I'm the second youngest executive in this company.
我現在已經擁有自己的辦公室。我是公司第二個最年輕的經理
The only one younger is a grandson of the chairman of the board.
另一個年輕人是董事長的孫子
[whistles] Do you mind?
覺得怎麼樣？
Miss Kubelik, I would like your honest opinion.
庫伯利克小姐，我想聽聽你的真實意見
I've had this under my desk for a week. It cost me $15.
我已經放在我辦公室桌子下面一個星期了，還花了我15美元
I haven't been able to get up enough nerve to wear it.
我還沒有完全準備好去戴它
It's what they call the Junior Executive model. What do you think?
這是他們說的高級經理的模樣，你認為怎麼樣？
I guess I made a boo-boo, huh?
我想我是不是犯了一個愚蠢的錯誤，呃？
- I like it. - Really?
- 我覺得很好 - 真的嗎？
You wouldn't be ashamed to be seen with somebody in this hat?
你不要覺得戴這帽子很丟人
- Of course not. - Maybe if I wore it a little to one side.
- 當然不會 - 也許如果我往這邊歪一點
- Is that better? - Much better.
- 那樣是不是好些？ - 好多了
Since you wouldn't be ashamed to be seen with me, ...
既然你不怕被我看到你戴這帽子.
.. how about gain' out tonight - you, me and the bowler?
我們今天晚上出去如何，你，我，還有這高帽子
We'll stroll down 5th Avenue, sort of break it in.
我們在第五大街逛逛，好好休息一下
- This is a bad day for me. - I understand. Christmas and family.
- 今天我心情不太好 - 我明白，聖誕節不能和家人在一起
I'd better get back to my elevator or I'll be fired.
我要回去了，否則我會被炒掉的.
Don't worry about that. I've got quite a bit of influence with Personnel.
不要擔心，我想我在人事部還有一些影響力
You know Mr Sheldrake?
你認識捨爾爵克先生嗎？
- Why? - He and I are like that.
- 怎麼了？ - 他和我的關係就像這樣
Sent me a Christmas card. See?
他送給我一張聖誕卡片，看到沒有？
Makes a cute picture.
很漂亮的卡片
I could talk to Mr Sheldrake. Get you a promotion.
我會和捨爾爵克先生說讓他提升你
- Would you like to be an elevator starter? - Too many girls have seniority over me.
你想做一個電梯操作班長嗎？太多女孩比我優秀
No problem. Why don't we discuss it over the holidays?
沒有問題，為什麼我們不討論一下假期呢？
I could call you, pick you up, have a big unveiling. Am I wearing this right?
我會給你打電話，邀請你出來，讓大家都知道，還有我戴這頂帽子！
I think so. Here.
我知道了，這裏
It's not tilted too much? This is a conservative firm.
是不是翹得太厲害了？這是一家很保守的公司
I don't want people to think I'm an entertainer.
我不想讓人們誤認為我是一個譁眾取寵的人
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
- The mirror. It's broken. - Yes, I know.
- 你的鏡子，好像破了。 - 是的，我知道
I like it that way. Makes me look the way I feel.
我喜歡這樣。讓我可以按照我想要的方式照鏡子
Your phone.
你的電話
Yes?
是嗎？
Uh,just a minute.
哦，等一下
- If you don't mind, this is sort of personal. - Have a nice Christmas.
- 如果你不介意的話，這是一個私人電話。 - 聖誕快樂
Yes, Mr Sheldrake.
捨爾爵克先生
No, I didn't forget. The tree is up and the Tom and Jerry mix is in the refrigerator.
不，我沒有忘，我家的聖誕樹已經做好了，湯姆和傑瑞的禮物我都放在冰箱了
Yes, sir. Same to you.
是的，聖誕快樂
Hey! Where are you gain', Buddy-boy?
嘿，你準備去哪兒，巴德小伙？
The party's just starting.
晚會才開始
Listen, kid. Gimme a break. How about tomorrow afternoon?
聽著，小伙子，給我安排一個時間，明天下午如何？
I can't take her to that drive-in again. The car has no heater. Four o'clock. OK?
我再也不能帶她去車上做愛了，汽車沒有空調？四點如何，好嗎？
Hey, Charlie! Gimme a shot of bourbon, and step on it! My sleigh is double-parked!
嗨，查理，給我一小杯波旁，快上來，我的雪橇是雙人座
You buy me a drink, I'll buy you some music.
你給我買一杯酒，我給你放一些音樂
Rum Collins.
羅姆克林斯
Uh ...
呃…
Rum Collins and ___ another one of these little mothers_
羅姆克林斯…這些年輕母親之一
You like Castro?
你喜歡卡斯特羅嗎？
I mean, how do you feel about Castro?
我的意思是說你對卡斯特羅的看法如何？
- What is Castro? - You know. That big shot down in Cuba.
- 誰是卡斯特羅？ - 你知道的，古巴的大人物
- With the crazy beard. - What about him?
- 留著一個大鬍子 - 他怎麼了
Cos as far as I'm concerned, he's a no-good fink.
因為據我所知，他是一個不折不扣的大流氓
Two weeks ago I wrote him a letter. Never even answered me.
兩個星期之前，我給他寫信他卻沒有給我回復
That so?
那又怎麼樣？
All I wanted him to do was let Mickey out for Christmas.
我讓他做的就只是放米奇出來過聖誕節
- Who's Mickey? - My husband.
- 誰是米奇？ - 我丈夫
He's in Havana, in jail.
他現在在哈瓦那坐牢
- Mixed up in that revolution? - Mickey would do nothin' like that.
- 他參加了那次革命嗎？ - 米奇不會坐那樣的事情的
He's a jockey. They caught him dopin' a horse.
他是一個訓馬師，他們讓他訓馬
Well, you can't win 'em all.
哦，那你不要對他們抱什麼希望
Twas the night before Christmas, and all through the house
今天是聖誕前夜，整棟房子
Not a creature was stirrin' ...
沒有一點生氣…
Nothin'. No action.
什麼都沒有，一點動靜都沒有
Dullsville.
極度沉悶，無聊至極
- You married? - No.
- 你結婚了嗎？ - 沒有
- Family? - No.
- 有家庭嗎？
A night like this, it sort of spooks you to walk into an empty apartment.
這樣的一個夜晚，想你這樣的幽靈走進一間空蕩蕩的公寓
I said I had no family. I didn't say I had an empty apartment.
我說我沒有家庭，這不代表我的公寓就是空蕩蕩的
Come on, Fran. Don't be that way.
快點，弗蘭，不要這樣子了
Are you just gonna sit there and keep bawling?
你還打算坐在這裏不停地抱怨我嗎？
You won't talk to me? You won't tell me what's wrong?
為什麼不和我說話呢？你總要告訴我哪裏做錯了吧
I know you think I'm stalling you but... when you've been married for 12 years, ...
我知道你認為我在推托你…假設當你結婚12年後
.. you just don't sit down to breakfast and say "Pass the sugar. I want a divorce."
你能硬下心腸說「我已經厭倦了，咱們離婚吧！」
It's not that easy.
很多事情不是想像的那麼容易
Anyway, this is the wrong time. The kids are off school, my in-laws are visiting.
總之，現在的時機還不成熟，我兒子正在放假，岳父母也還在我家裏住著
I can't bring it up now.
我不能現在和他們撕破臉皮，
This isn't like you, Fran. You were always such a good sport. Such fun to be with.
這不像你啊，弗蘭，你是個非常開朗的女孩，和你在一起總是很開心的
That's me. The happy idiot. A laughs.
對，我是一個快樂的傻瓜，總被人笑話
Well, that's a little more like it. At least you're speaking to me.
好了，這樣才對嘛，至少你能和我說話了
A funny thing happened to me at the office party today.
今天公司晚會我碰到了一件有趣的事情
I ran into your secretary, Miss Olsen.
我碰到了你的秘書，奧爾森小姐
You know. Ring-a-ding-ding?
你知道的，一個曾經和你熱戀的人
And I laughed so much, I like to died.
我被她氣死了，我不想活了
Is that what's been bothering you, Fran? Miss Olsen? That's ancient history.
弗蘭，是這件事情在困擾你嗎？奧爾森小姐？都是陳年舊事了
Well, I never was very good at history.
哎呀，我的記性向來都不是太好
Let me see. There was Miss Olsen, and then there was Miss Rossi.
讓我來幫你想想，先是奧爾森小姐，然後是洛斯小姐
No, she came before. Miss Koch came after Miss Olsen.
不，她還在前面，奧爾森小姐，後面是科其小姐
- Now, Fran ... - And just think.
好了，弗蘭…你現在想一想
Right now some lucky girl in the building is gonna come after me.
這個房子裏是不是還要有人像我一樣成為你的幸運女孩？
OK. OK, Fran. I guess I deserved that.
不要說了，弗蘭，我想也許是我罪有應得
But ask yourself: why does a man run around with a lot of girls?
但是你問問你自己：為什麼一個男人會追求這麼多的女孩，這麼花心？
Because he's unhappy at home. Because he's lonely. That's why.
因為他在家裏不開心，因為他很孤獨，這才是真正的原因
But that was before you, Fran. I've stopped running.
這些都在你之前，弗蘭，我現在已經不再花心了
How could I be so stupid? You'd think I would've learned by now.
我怎麼會這麼愚蠢呢？你肯定在想我早就被你吃透了
When you're in love with a married man, you shouldn't wear mascara.
當你愛上一個已婚男人的時候，就注定沒有好結局。
It's Christmas Eve, Fran. Let's not fight, huh?
弗蘭，今天是聖誕夜，我們不要吵架，好嗎？
- Merry Christmas. - What is it?
- 聖誕快樂！ - 這是什麼？
Oh. Our friend at the Chinese restaurant.
我們中餐廳朋友送的
- Thanks, Fran. We'd better keep it here. - Yeah, we'd better.
- 謝謝，弗蘭，我們最好把它放在這裏。 - 是的。
Oh, I have a present for you.
對了，我也為你準備了一份禮物
I didn't know what to get you. Besides, it's kind of awkward for me shopping, so ...
我不知道給你買什麼東西好，另外…我也很不喜歡去逛街買東西，因此…
Here's $100. You go and buy yourself something.
我給你100美元，你自己看著喜歡什麼就買什麼吧！
They have some nice alligator bags at Bergdorfs.
在伯格道夫專賣店有一些很好的鱷魚皮包
I didn't realise it was so late. It's quarter to seven. I mustn't miss my train.
想不到現在這麼晚了，都已經七點差十分了，我現在必須去趕火車去了
If we hadn't wasted all this time ... I have to get home and trim the tree.
如果不是我們已經浪費了這麼多時間的話，我可能現在已經到家修剪聖誕樹了
OK. I just thought, as long as it was paid for ...
那好，我就當作是我陪你的報酬
Don't ever talk like that, Fran.
弗蘭，不要這樣說話
- Don't make yourself out to be cheap. - $100? I don't call that cheap.
不要把自己說得這麼不值錢，100美元？我才不會這麼便宜的！
And you must be paying somebody something for the use of the apartment.
你是不是還給這間公寓的人付過錢了？
Stop it, Fran.
住嘴，弗蘭
You'll miss your train, Jeff.
傑夫，你快趕不上火車了
Are you coming?
你和我一起出去嗎？
No, you run along. I'm gonna fix my face.
不，你先走，我還要補補妝
Don't forget to kill the lights. See you Monday.
不要忘記關燈，我們星期一見
Sure. Monday ... and Thursday ...
好的，星期一…星期四
.. and Monday again, and Thursday again.
然後又是星期一，又是星期四
It won't always be like this, Fran.
弗蘭，這種情況不會很久的
I love you.
我愛你
Careful. Lipstick.
小心一點，不要沾到口紅了
Merry Christmas.
聖誕快樂
- Drink up, pop. It's closing time. - But it's early, Charlie.
- 快喝完，要關門了 - 還早呢，查理
- Don't you know what night this is? - I know, Charlie. I know.
- 難道你不知道今天是什麼日子嗎？ - 我知道，查理
I work for the outfit.
我為一個團體工作
Hey, knock it off, will ya? Go home.
嗨，快停下來，聽到沒有？快回家
O-U-T. Out!
出去！出去！
Where'li we go? My place or yours?
我們去哪裏？我的地方還是你的？
Might as well go to mine. Everybody else does.
最好到我那裏去，他們每個人都這樣干
Poor Mickey. When I think of him all by himself in that jail in Havana ...
可憐的寶貝，我還在想那個在哈瓦那坐牢的可憐蟲
Would you like to see his picture?
你想看看他的照片嗎？
Not particularly.
不是很想看
He's so cute. He's 5 foot 2, 99 pounds.
他很聰明，身高5英尺2英吋，99磅
Like a little Chihuahua.
就像一個吉娃娃那樣可愛
- Can I ask you a personal question? - No.
- 我能問你一個私人的問題嗎？ - 沒問題
You got a girlfriend?
你有女朋友嗎？
She may be a girl but she is no friend of mine.
她可能是一個姑娘，但她不是我的女朋友
- Still stuck on her, huh? - Obviously you don't know me very well.
- 你還想她，不是嗎？ - 很明顯你不太瞭解我
- I don't know you at all. - Permit me.
- 我根本不瞭解你 - 讓我來自我介紹一下
CC Baxter. Junior executive, Arthur Murray graduate ... lover.
CC·巴克斯特，高級經理，亞瑟墨裏大學畢業，還不錯吧
I'm Mrs MacDougall. Margie to you.
我叫麥戈道格拉斯·馬吉夫人
This way, Mrs MacDougall.
這邊走，麥戈道格拉斯夫人
Say! This is snugsville!
哦，這是一間單身公寓
Mrs MacDougall, it's only fair to warn you ...
麥戈道格拉斯夫人，我要警告你，不要亂說話。
.. you are now alone with a notorious sexpot.
你現在是和我這樣一個如饑似渴的風騷女人一起。
- No kiddin'! - Ask anybody around here.
- 別逗了 - 問問這附近的人
As a matter of fact, when it's time for me to go - and I may go just like that -
事實上，往常這個時候我都要離開這裏的，十分不爽
I have promised my body to the Columbia Medical Center.
我已經承諾把我的身體在我上天堂後捐給哥倫比亞醫學研究中心
Gee! Sort of gives you goose bumps just to think about it.
切！你這種大笨鵝才會這樣想
They haven't got me yet, baby. Dig up some ice from the kitchen.
寶貝，他們還沒有最後拿走我的身體，從廚房拿些冰出來
Let's not waste any more time preliminarywise.
春宵一刻值千金，快點來啊
I'm with you, lover.
我就來，親愛的
All right, Miss Kubelik. Get up.
好了，庫伯利克小姐，快起來
Come on. It's past checking-out time.
快點，時間已經過了
The management would appreciate it if you'd get the hell outta here.
如果你現在從這裏出去，我會對你感激不盡的
I used to like you. I used to like you a lot. Well, it's all over between us, so beat it.
我是曾經喜歡你，非常的喜歡你，可是…我們之間已經沒有什麼了，快走開
O-U-T, out!
出去！出——去！
Come on, wake up.
快點，快醒醒
Oh my God.
哦，天啊
Miss Kubelik?
庫伯利克小姐？
I broke a nail tryin' to get the tray out.
為了把這個破托盤拿出來，我的指甲也被弄斷了
You oughta buy yourself a new refrigerator.
你應該買一個新冰箱了
I didn't mean right now!
我不是指現在
Dr Dreyfuss.
爵發斯醫生
Doc!
醫生
There's a girl in my place, took some sleeping pills. I can't wake her up.
我這裏有一位姑娘吃了很多安眠藥，我叫不醒她
- Let me get my bag. - Hurry up!
- 等我拿一下我的醫藥包 - 快一點
Hey, over here, lover. What's all the running around about?
嘿，在這裏，親愛的！你跑來跑去幹什麼？
You're gonna wear yourself out.
你現在自己穿衣服出去
- Not so rough, honey! - Good night.
- 不要這麼粗魯，親愛的 - 晚安
- Good night?! - The party's over.
- 晚安？ - 聚會結束了
What? Did I do somethin' wrong?
什麼？難道我做錯了什麼嗎？
It's an emergency. I'll see you some other time.
是一個意外，我們再約時間吧
Not this one. In there, Doc.
不是這一個，在那裏，醫生
- What's gain' on here, anyway? - Will you please just get out?!
- 這裏到底發生什麼了？ - 你能現在給我出去嗎？
My shoes!
我的鞋！
Some lover you are! Some sexpot!
你是這麼的可人，性感！
Here. Find a phone. Call your husband in Havana.
快去找一個電話亭，給你哈瓦那的老公打個電話
You bet I will! And when I tell him how you treated me, he'll push your face in!
你說對了，我會告訴他你怎麼對待我的，他會把你揍成豬頭一樣
You fink!
人渣！
Is she gonna be all right, Doc?
她沒事吧，醫生？
- How many pills were in that bottle? - It was half-full. About a dozen.
- 那瓶裏還有多少安眠藥 - 大概半瓶吧，12粒左右
- Do you have to take her to the hospital? - Help me, will you?
- 你不需要把她送到醫院吧？ - 幫幫我，好嗎？
- Into the bathroom. - What are you gonna do?
- 快把她扶到洗手間 - 你有什麼打算？
Get that stuff out of her stomach if it isn't too late.
讓她把安眠藥吐出來，希望不要太遲
You'd better put some coffee on, and pray.
你要幹的事情就是沖好一些咖啡，然後待在一邊祈禱
Bring my bag.
拿著我的包
Roll up her right sleeve.
把她右邊的袖子捲起來
Hold that.
拿著
Nice veins.
好美麗的血管
Wanna tell me what happened?
能告訴我發生什麼事情了嗎？
I don't know. I mean, I wasn't even here.
我不知道，我的意思是，開始我根本不在這裏
You see, we had ... some words earlier.
你知道的，我們前段時間不是討論過這樣的事情嘛
It was nothin' serious. You might call it a lovers' quarrel.
沒有什麼嚴重，事實上就是我們情人間的吵架
So you went right out and picked yourself up another dame.
於是你就跑出去，很快就認識了另外一位夫人
- Something like that. - You know, Baxter, you're a real cutie pie.
就是那，你知道，巴克斯特，你還是很討人喜歡的
Yes, you are.
對，確實如此
If you'd come home half an hour later, you'd have had quite a Christmas present.
如果你晚回來半個小時的，你可能已經收到一份特別的聖誕節禮物
Get the coffee.
把咖啡拿過來
Let's get some air in here. Open the windows.
把窗戶打開透透氣
What's her name?
她叫什麼名字？
Miss Kubelik. Fran.
庫伯利克·弗蘭小姐
Fran, I'm a doctor. I'm here because you took too many sleeping pills.
弗蘭，我是一個醫生，我在這裏是因為你吃了過量的安眠藥
Do you understand what I'm saying?
你明白我說什麼嗎？
Fran, I'm Dr Dreyfuss. I'm here to help you.
弗蘭，我是爵福斯醫生，我是來幫你的
You took all those sleeping pills. Remember?
你吃了那所有的安眠藥？還記得嗎？
- Sleeping pills. - That's right, Fran. And I'm a doctor.
- 安眠藥 - 對，弗蘭，我還是個醫生
- Doctor? - Dr Dreyfuss.
- 醫生？ - 爵福斯醫生
Dreyfuss.
爵福斯
Get more coffee.
再多拿點咖啡過來
Now tell me again. What's my name?
現在你再告訴我，我叫什麼名字？
Dr ... Dreyfuss.
爵福斯醫生
And what happened to you?
你剛才幹了什麼？
I...
我…
I took sleeping pills.
我吃了安眠藥
Do you know where you are?
你知道你現在在哪裏嗎？
- No. - Yes, you do, Fran. Now concentrate!
- 不知道 - 好，做得很好，弗蘭，現在要集中精神
I don't know.
我不知道
Do you know who that is?
你知道他是誰嗎？
Look at him.
看著他
Mr Baxter. 19th floor.
19樓的巴克斯特先生
Hello, Miss Kubelik.
你好，庫伯利克小姐
Mr? Miss? Such politeness!
先生？小姐？你們怎麼這麼客氣啊？
We work in the same building. We try to keep it quiet.
我們在同一棟大廈工作，我們不想驚動別人
What are you doing here?
你在這裏幹什麼？
Don't you remember we were together at the office party?
你還記得我們在公司的晚會上在一起嗎？
Oh, yes. The office party.
哦，是的，公司晚會
- Miss Olsen. - That's right.
- 還有奧爾森小姐 - 對
I told you we had a fight. That was what it was about.
我告訴你我們吵了一架，這就是整件事情的緣由
Miss Olsen. That girl that was here earlier.
奧爾森小姐開始的時候也在這裏
I don't understand.
我不明白
The main thing is I got here in time and you're gonna be all right. Isn't she, Doc?
整件事情就是我及時趕回，你也沒事了，你說呢，醫生
I'm so tired.
我很累
Come on.Drinkthis.
快點，把這些喝下去
Please ... just let me sleep.
求求你了…讓我睡覺吧！
No, you can't sleep! Fran, open your eyes!
不行，你現在不能睡覺。聽著，弗蘭，睜開眼睛
Let's get her walking.
讓我們來扶著她走路
We've got to keep her awake for the next few hours. Now come on, Fran, walk!
在接下來的幾個小時我們必須讓她保持清醒。快點，弗蘭，走路
One, two, three, four!
1，2，3，4
Left, right, left, right, ...
左，右，左，右…
.. Ieft, right and return!
…左，右，再來！
And ... one, two, three, four!
1，2，3，4！
Now you've got it! One, two, three, four!
就這樣，繼續！1，2，3，4
Walk, Fran! One, two, three, four!
走路，弗蘭！1，2，3，4
One, two ... And return again.
左，右，再來！
And ... left, right, left, right.
左，右，左，右…
She'll sleep on and off for the next 24 hours.
在接下來的24小時內，她會時醒時睡
Of course, she'll have a dandy hangover when she wakes up.
好的，等她醒了，她還需要好好的睡上一覺才行
Just as long as she's OK.
直到她完全好了為止
These cases are harder on the doctor than the patient. I oughta charge by the mile.
這些活兒對於醫生來說比病人更辛苦，我應該按照公里收費
- Any of that coffee left? - Yeah, sure.
- 還有咖啡嗎？ - 是的，當然有
How do you spell her last name?
她的名字怎麼拼？
Kubelik. Two k's.
庫伯利克，兩個K
What's her address?
她的地址？
Where does she live?
她住在哪裏？
Why do you wanna know, Doc?
醫生，你問這些有什麼用？
- You don't have to report this, do you? - It's regulations.
- 你不用報告這些東西不是嗎？ - 這是慣例
But it was an accident. She had too much to drink, didn't know what she was doing.
這是個意外，她喝太多了，都不知道自己在幹什麼！
There was no suicide note or anything.
不要給她留下什麼自殺或者其他的記錄
- I'm not thinkin' about myself. - Aren't you?
- 我要為她著想！ - 你也是吧！
She's got a family, and there's the people at the office.
她還有家，辦公室的同事
Can't you forget you're a doctor, just say you're here as a neighbour?
你能不能忘記你是一個醫生，只是把自己當作我的鄰居
Well, as a doctor, I can't prove it wasn't an accident.
好吧，作為一個醫生，我不能說這是一個意外！
But as your neighbour, I'd like to kick you around the block.
但是作為你的鄰居，我很想揍你一頓
- Mind if I cool this off? - Help yourself.
- 我把這個冷凍一下你介意嗎？ - 自便
I don't know what you did to that girl, ...
我不知道你對這個女孩作了什麼
.. but it was bound to happen, the way you carry on.
但是現在事情都已經發生了，不管你是採取什麼方式
Live now, pay later. Diners Club!
種瓜得瓜，種豆得豆，不管什麼結果，都是需要你自己承擔的
Why don't you grow up, Baxter? Be a mensch.
巴克斯特，你為什麼這麼不成熟呢？你要成為一個高尚的人
- You know what that means? - I'm not sure.
- 你知道我什麼意思嗎？ - 不是很明確
A mensch/ A human being!
一個高尚的人，一個真正受人尊敬的人
SO you got off easy this time. So you were lucky.
這次你幸運逃脫，這是你的運氣
But you're not out of the woods yet, because most of 'em try it again.
但是你不可能老是這麼走運的，因為江山易改，本性難移，你還是會這樣干
Well, you know where I am if you need me.
好了，如果你需要我，你應該知道在哪裏找我
Mr Baxter! Open up already.
巴克斯特先生？這麼早就出去
Oh.
哦
- Mrs Lieberman. - Who did you think it was? Kriss Kringle?
- 李伯曼夫人 - 你以為是誰？克瑞斯·克瑞格？
What was going on here last night?
昨天晚上這裏怎麼了？
- Last night? - All that marching! Tramp, tramp, tramp!
昨晚？好像在行軍一樣！咚咚咚的！
- Army manoeuvres maybe? - I'll never invite those people again.
可能是軍隊演習吧？我再也不會邀請那些傢伙了
What you get from renting to bachelors. All night I didn't sleep ten minutes.
把房子出租給單身漢感覺好吧？整晚上都沒有睡個10分鐘的安穩覺
- And I'm sure you woke up Dr Dreyfuss. - Don't worry. He was out on a case.
- 我肯定你把爵福斯醫生喊起來了 - 不要擔心，他現在出去看病去了
I'm warning you, Mr Baxter. This is a respectable house, not a honky-tonky.
巴克斯特先生，我警告你：這是高級公寓，不是下等旅社。
Come on, Oscar.
快點，奧斯卡
Operator, I want White Plains, New York. Mr JD Sheldrake.
總機，請幫我接通白色莊園的JD·捨爾爵克先生的電話
Make that person-to-person.
記住這是一個私人電話
Five, four, three, two, one ...
5，4，3，2，1…
- Let her rip! - [phone rings]
讓她全速前進
I'll get the phone.
我來接電話
Hey, Dad, why don't we put a fly in the nose cone?
爸爸，為什麼我們不在火箭這裏放一隻蒼蠅呢
- See if we can bring it back alive. - That's a thought.
- 如果我們能把它活著帶回來的話 - 好主意
Maybe we should put in two flies and see if they'll propagate in orbit.
也許我們能夠放兩隻蒼蠅，看他們能不能在太空中繁殖
- See if they'll what? - Propagate. You know. Multiply.
- 看她們能幹什麼？ - 繁殖啊，你知道，就是生小蒼蠅
- Baby flies? - Oh. Oh!
- 小蒼蠅 - 呵，呵
- It's for you, Dad. - Thanks, Jeff.
- 你的電話，爸爸 - 謝謝，傑夫
A Mr Baxter. Person-to-person.
一個叫巴克斯特的先生，說是私人電話
Come on. Help me round up some flies.
快點，幫我放一些蒼蠅
- Hello? What's on your mind, Baxter? - Something came up that's important.
- 你好？巴克斯特先生，你腦子出問題了麼？ - 發生了一些很重要的事情
I think you should see me at the apartment as soon as possible.
我想你最好盡快趕到我的公寓和我見面
- What's this all about? - I didn't wanna tell you over the phone.
- 究竟是怎麼回事？ - 我不想在電話上談這件事情
But that certain party ... You know who I mean. I found her here last night.
在晚會後，你知道我的意思，我昨天晚上在我的公寓發現她了
- She took an overdose of sleeping pills. - What?!
- 她服用了大量的安眠藥 - 什麼？
- What is it, Jeff? Who's on the phone? - One of our employees had an accident.
- 傑夫，是誰啊，你和誰講電話呢？ - 我們的一個員工出了意外
I don't know why they bother me with these things on Christmas Day.
我不知道為什麼他們總是在聖誕節用這些事情來煩我
Yes, Baxter.
是的，巴克斯特先生
Just how serious is it?
情況有多嚴重
It was touch and go there for a while, but she's sleeping it off now.
還好，危險期已經過了，但是她現在還在沉睡
I thought maybe you'd like to be here when she wakes up.
我想你最好當她醒來的時候能在這裏
That's impossible. You'll have to handle the situation yourself, Baxter.
那不可能，巴克斯特，你要一個人幫我搞定這件事情
- As a matter of fact, I'm counting on you. - Yes, sir. I understand.
- 事實上，我非常相信你的能力 - 知道，先生，我明白
She left a letter. Would you like me to open it and read it to you?
她留下一封信，你需要我現在打開給你讀信的內容嗎？
Well, it was just a suggestion.
當然，這只是一個建議
No, don't worry. I kept your name out of it, so there'll be no trouble, ...
而且我已經把你的名字擦掉了，你不用擔心
.. policewise or newspaperwise.
警察局或者媒體方面會有什麼麻煩
You see, the doctor is a friend of mine, so we were very lucky in that respect.
你知道，這個醫生是我的朋友，這方面你也不用太過擔心
Actually, he thinks she's my girl.
事實上，他都以為她是我的女朋友
No, he just jumped to the conclusion.
這只是他的錯誤判斷
Around here I'm known as quite a ladies' man.
在這附近我被他們認為是一個花花公子
Of course, we're not out of the woods yet. Sometimes they try it again.
當然，我們現在還沒有完全脫離危險，有時候，他們還會找麻煩的
Yes, sir. I'll do my best. It'll take her a couple of days to fully recover ...
我明白，我會盡量擺平這一切，估計她可能還要好幾天才能完全康復
.. and I may have a little problem with the landlady.
而且房東太太那裏還會有一些麻煩
Alright, Mr Sheldrake. I'll keep her in the apartment as long as I can.
好了，捨爾爵克先生，我會盡可能的把她留在公寓裏
Isn't there some sort of message you want me to give her?
你需要我給你傳些什麼口信嗎？
Well, I'll ... think of something.
哦，讓我想想
Yes, sir. Goodbye, Mr Sheldrake.
好吧，再見，捨爾爵克先生
I'm sorry.
對不起
- I'm sorry, Mr Baxter. - What are you doing out of bed?
- 非常抱歉，巴克斯特先生。 - 你怎麼能下床亂走呢？
I didn't know. I had no idea this was your apartment.
我不知道這會是你的公寓
Here. Let me help you.
到這裏，我來幫你
Oh, I'm so ashamed.
我沒臉活下去了
Why didn't you just let me die?
你為什麼不讓我死呢？
What kind of talk is that? You got a little overemotional, but you're fine now.
這是什麼話？你只是情緒有些失控，但是現在一切都過去了
Oh!
哦
Oh, my head! It feels just like a big wad of chewing gum.
我的頭好痛，好想要裂了一樣
- What time is it? - Two o'clock.
- 現在幾點了？ - 2點
Oh, my dress. I have to go home.
我的衣服到哪裏去了，我現在要回家
You're in no shape to go anywhere but back to bed.
你現在不適合到任何地方去，只能馬上給我回到床上去
- You don't want me here. - Sure I do. 1...
- 你不希望我在這裏 - 怎麼會呢
It's always nice to have company for Christmas.
聖誕節的時候有人做伴真好
- I'm stronger than you are. - I just wanna brush my teeth.
我沒事，我只想刷牙
Oh. Of course. I think I can find a new toothbrush somewhere.
哦，當然可以，我想你可以在那裏找到一個新的牙刷
Here. Put that on.
在這裏，把衣服穿上
- How about some breakfast? - No. I don't want anything.
- 想吃點早餐嗎？ - 不，我沒有胃口
I'll fix you some coffee.
我來給你倒一些咖啡吧！
Oh! We're all out of coffee. You had quite a lot last night.
哦，竟然都喝光了，你昨天晚上喝太多了
Back in a minute.
我馬上回來
Mrs Dreyfuss, could I borrow some coffee?
爵福斯太太，你能借我一些咖啡嗎
- And an orange and a couple of eggs? - Eggs, he asks me for! Oranges!
- 加一個桔子和兩個雞蛋？ - 雞蛋，他為我要的，還有桔子！
What you need is a good horsewhipping! From me the doctor has no secrets.
你現在需要好好補補身體，我老公，就是你的醫生，從來都不對我隱瞞的
Poor girl. How could you do such a thing?
可憐的姑娘，幹什麼要幹這樣的傻事呢
I didn't do anything. Honest. It's just...
我什麼也沒幹，實話說，這只是…
You take a girl out just for laughs and she thinks you're serious marriagewise.
你和她在一起只是為了玩樂，而她卻認為你值得托付終身
Big shot! For you, I wouldn't lift a finger!
大人物，對於你，我才懶的伺候你
But for her, I'll fix a little something to eat.
但對於她，我將會準備一些東西餵她吃
Who are you calling?
你在和誰打電話？
My sister, to tell her what happened to me.
我姐姐，告訴她我發生什麼事了
Wait a minute! Let's talk it over first. Just what are you gonna tell her?
等一下，我們先來談一談，你打算告訴她什麼？
- I haven't figured it out exactly. - Well, you'd better figure it out exactly.
- 我還沒有太明確的打算 - 好的，你最好想清楚一些
Suppose she asks you why you didn't come home last night.
假設她問你昨天晚上為什麼不回家，你會怎麼回答？
I'll say I spent the night with a friend.
我會說陪一個朋友
- Who? - Someone from the office.
- 誰？ - 公司的同事
- Where are you now? - In his apartment.
- 你現在在哪裏？ - 在他的公寓
- In his apartment? - In her apartment.
- 他的公寓 - 在她的公寓
- What's your friend's name? - Baxter.
- 你朋友叫什麼名字？ - 巴克斯特
- What's her first name? - Miss.
- 她姓什麼？ - 不記得了
- When are you comin' home? - As soon as I can walk.
- 你什麼時候回家 - 直到我能走路為止
- Your legs hurt? - No, my stomach.
- 你的腿受傷了嗎？ - 不是，是我的胃不舒服
- Your stomach? - They had to pump it out!
- 你的胃？ - 他們一定會盤問到底的
You shouldn't call anybody. Not till you get the chewing gum out of your head.
你現在不能給任何人打電話，直到你完全清醒為止
They'll be worried about me. They might call the police.
他們會擔心我的，可能會報警的
We have to be careful. We don't wanna involve anybody.
我們必須要非常小心，我們不想牽連任何人
After all, Mr Sheldrake's a married man.
畢竟，捨爾爵克先生已經結婚了
Thanks for reminding me[!]
謝謝提醒我
I didn't mean it that way.
我不是這個意思
I was just talking to him on the phone. He's very concerned about you.
我剛才和他通過電話，他非常關心你
He doesn't give a damn about me.
他沒有罵我嗎？
- You're wrong. He told me ... - He's a liar.
你錯了，他告訴我一一他這個大騙子
But that's not the worst part.
這根本不算是最壞的情形
The worst part is I still love him.
最糟糕的是我還愛他
[doorbell]
哦，肯定是爵福斯夫人過來了
Remember the doctor from last night? That's his wife.
記得昨天晚上來的醫生嗎？她是他的妻子
So where's the victim?
我們的受害人在哪裏呢？
Max the Knife!
拿看刀
- Nu, little lady, how are we feeling today? - I don't know. Kind of dizzy.
- 呃，小姐，今天感覺如何？ - 我不知道，只是有一些暈
The best thing for dizzy is noodle soup with chicken white meat and a glass tea.
治頭暈最好的辦法就是雞湯肉絲面，再來一杯茶
- No, thank you. I'm really not hungry. - Go ahead, eat. Enjoy.
- 不用，謝謝，我真的不餓 - 快吃點，對你身體很好的
You wouldn't have such a thing as a napkin, would you?
你不會把這東西當餐巾吧？
- I have some paper towels. - Beatnik.
- 我有一些紙巾 - 不像話，真是垮掉的一代
In my kitchen, third drawer, under the good silver, are napkins.
在我的廚房，第三格，餐巾就放在銀餐具下面
Yes, Mrs Dreyfuss.
好的，爵福斯太太
So, what are you waiting for? A singing commercial?
那你還等什麼呢？看戲呢？
- I can't eat. - You must eat.
- 我吃不下 - 你必須吃一點
And you must get healthy and you must forget him.
你必須好起來，忘記這個薄情寡義的傢伙
Such a fine boy he seemed when he first moved in here.
當他第一次搬進來的時候，我覺得他還是一個好小伙子
Clean and cut, a regular Ivy Leaguer.
整潔幹練，一個前途無量的大學生
Turns out he's King Farouk, with the drinking, with the cha-cha.
結果他卻是一個喜歡喝酒、跳恰恰舞的毫無品位
With the no napkins.
還沒有餐巾
A girl like you, for the rest of your life you wanna cry in your noodle soup?
像你這樣的一個女孩，你願意讓你的後半生充滿悲傷嗎？
Who needs it? Now you listen to me.
誰會需要呢？你現在聽我說
You'll find yourself a nice, substantial man - a widower, maybe -
你肯定會找到一個非常好的很有潛力的男人，或者一個鑽石王老五
and settle down, instead of noshing all those sleeping pills.
成立一個幸福美滿的家庭，而不是吃安眠藥
For what? For whom? For some good-time Charlie?
為什麼？為誰呢？為一些喜歡社交與享樂的人？
One napkin comin' up. Wish we had some champagne to wrap it around.
餐巾拿到了，我們喝些香檳如何
- What did I tell you? - Mrs Dreyfuss, you don't have to wait.
- 我告訴你什麼了？ - 爵福斯太太，你不需要在這裏等
- I'll wash the dishes. - You'd break 'em. I'll come back for them.
我要回去洗碗去了，你現在休息一下，這些東西等我回來拿
If he makes trouble, give me a yell.
如果他欺負你，就叫我一聲
- She doesn't seem to like you very much. - Oh, I don't mind.
- 她好像不太喜歡你啊 - 哦，沒關係，我不在乎
As a matter of fact, I'm sort of flattered.
實際上，我反而覺得受寵若驚
That anybody'd think a girl like you would do a thing like this over a guy like me.
他們都認為像你這樣的女孩會為了像我這樣的人做這樣的傻事
Did you find something here? An envelope?
你看到這裏的東西沒有？一個信封？
Yes. I've got it.
是的，在我這裏
Don't you think we'd better destroy it so it won't fall in the wrong hands?
你覺得我們是不是最好把它銷毀，這樣就不會給別人抓到把柄
Open it.
打開
There's nothing here but a $100 bill.
這裏什麼也沒有，就只有100美元
That's right. Will you see that Mr Sheldrake gets it?
是的，你是不是想讓捨爾爵克拿到這東西
Sure.
當然
Take this away, will you?
把這拿開，好嗎？
Would you like me to move the television set in here?
想不想看電視？要不我把它移過來
- You play gin rummy? - I'm not very good at it.
- 你會玩拉米紙牌嗎？ - 不太會
- I am. Let me get the cards. - You don't have to entertain me.
- 我會，我們來玩牌吧！ - 你不用陪我玩的
There's nothing I'd like better. You know. Togetherness.
你知道的，這裏沒有什麼可以讓我們兩個人一起玩的東西
Guess what I did last Christmas. Had dinner at the automat, went to the zoo, ...
猜猜上一個聖誕節我幹什麼，吃自助晚餐，逛逛動物園
.. then came home and cleaned up after Mr Eichelberger.
然後回家，在艾其伯格走了以後打掃衛生
He had a little eggnog party here.
他在這裏開了一個蛋酒晚會
So I'm way ahead this year.
所以今年我就一個人清清靜靜的過
Three across. Spades double?
3叉，兩個黑桃？
High deals.
好牌
Six? Eight.
6？8.
I think I'm gonna give it all up.
我想你要徹底放棄了.
Give what up?
放棄什麼？
Why do people have to love people, anyway?
為什麼人們必須相愛呢？
I know what you mean.
我知道你的意思。
Queen.
皇后(Q)
- I don't want it. - Pick a card.
- 我也不想這樣 - 快拿一張牌
What do you call it when somebody keeps gettin' smashed up in car accidents?
你認為一個人在出車禍的時候，還是糊里糊塗應該算什麼？
- Bad insurance risk? - That's me with men.
- 惡意索賠的危險？ - 那是我和男人
I was jinxed from the word go. First time I was ever kissed was in a cemetery.
人家都說我是白虎星。我的初吻是在一個墓地裏發生的.
A cemetery?
墓地裏？
I was 15. We used to go there to smoke.
那時我15歲，喜歡到那裏躲著抽煙
His name was George and he threw me over for a drum majorette.
他叫喬治，後來為了一個鼓隊長把我甩了
Uh,gin.
Uh，gin.
That's 10, 20 ... 36. And 25 makes 61 and two boxes.
10，20…36，再加上25就是61還有兩盒
I have this talent for falling in love ...
我總是容易陷入情網
.. with the wrong guy in the wrong place at the wrong time.
但總是在錯誤的時間、錯誤的地點愛上不該愛的人
Well, how many guys were there?
哦，那你總共愛上了幾個人？
Three.
三個
The last one was the manager of a finance company back home in Pittsburgh.
最近的一個是公司的財務經理，後來被遣送回匹茨伯格的老家
They found a shortage in his accounts.
他們發現他的賬目有巨大的差異
He asked me to wait for him. He'll be out in 1965.
他讓我等他，他是1965年走的
Cut.
切牌
So I came to New York and moved in with my sister and her husband, a cab driver.
於是我返回紐約並和我的姐姐，姐夫住在一起，他是出租車司機.
They sent me to secretarial school and then I applied for a job at Consolidated.
他們送我讀了一個秘書學校，然後我在聯合生活保險申請了一份工作
But I flunked the typing test.
但是我的打字考試不及格
- Too slow? - No. I can type up a storm.
- 太慢了？ - 不是，我打得飛快
I just can't spell.
我不會寫字
So they gave me a pair of white gloves and stuck me in an elevator.
於是他們給我一雙白手套，把我安置在電梯裏
And that's how I met Jeff.
於是我碰到了傑夫
Oh God, I'm so fouled up.
天啊，於是我被他纏上了
What am I gonna do now?
現在我能做什麼呢？
Better win a hand. You're on a blitz.
我又贏了你一手牌，你進展太快了
Was he very upset when you told him?
當你告訴他的時候，他是不是非常的難過？
Mr Sheldrake? Yeah, very.
捨爾爵克先生？是的，非常的心煩意亂
Maybe he does love me, only he doesn't have the nerve to tell his wife.
也許他確實愛我，只是沒有告訴他夫人的勇氣
I'm sure that's it.
我想也是的
- You really think so? - No doubt about it.
- 你真的這麼想？ - 毫無疑問
Would you hand me that pad and pencil?
你能遞給我那本便箋和鉛筆嗎？
- What for? - I'm gonna write to Mrs Sheldrake.
- 幹什麼用？ - 我想給捨爾爵克太太寫信
- You what? - As one woman to another.
- 寫什麼內容？ - 一個女人給另外一個女人寫信
- I'm sure she'll understand. - I don't think that's a very good idea.
- 我想她應該能理解我 - 我不認為這是一個非常好的主意
- Why not? - For one thing, you can't spell.
- 為什麼呢？ - 首先，你不會寫字
Secondly, if you did something like that, you'd hate yourself.
其次，如果你做了這樣的事情，你會恨你自己的
I don't like myself very much anyway.
我確實對我自己不滿意
Pick up the cards. Let's go.
把牌收起來，我們走！
- Do I have to? - You bet. I got a terrific ha nd.
- 我也要去嗎？ - 你說對了，我手上的牌太好了
- You really wanna discard that? - Sure.
- 你要把牌全扔了嗎？ - 當然
Gin.
Gin.
[hums nervously]
10，20，40，52再加上25就等於77
Spades are double ... 154.
方片翻倍就是154
Blitzed. Two games.
哈哈，我贏了兩盤了了
[Sylvia hums along to dance music]
好的，好的，爵福斯太太
- Hi, Baxter. - What do you want?
- 嘿，巴克斯特 - 你要幹什麼？
What do I want? Just a minute.
沒事，你們等一會
- You can't come in! - What's the matter with you?
- 你們不能進來 - 你怎麼了？
I made a reservation for four o'clock.
我預訂了四點鐘的房間啊
You can't stay. Take your champagne and go.
今天你不能呆在這裏，拿著你的香檳快離開這裏
I don't wanna pull rank on you, but I told the little lady it was all set.
我不想拿我的職位來壓你，但是我已經告訴那位女士一切都搞定了
Are you gonna leave, Mr Kirkeby, or do I have to throw you out?
科克比先生，你是自己離開，還是讓我把你扔出去
[sniggers] Buddy-boy, why didn't you say so?
哥們兒，不要這樣說話嘛！
- Got yourself a little playmate, huh? - Now will you get out?
- 你是不是也找了一個女伴？ - 現在你還不準備出去嗎？
[Sylvia hums dance music]
嘿，快點，我們還等什麼呢？開門，好不好？
[Dr Dreyfuss] Mildred!
米爾德裏德！
- What's holding things up? - Say, let's have a party, the four of us.
- 為什麼要這樣處理呢？ - 聽著，我們四個人一起開一個聚會，好嗎？
No!
不行
[sniggers] Well, I don't blame you.
好了，我也不想責怪你
So you hit the jackpot, eh, kid? I mean Kubelikwise.
小伙子，這回你中頭獎了？我是說和你和庫伯利克
Don't worry. I won't say a word to anybody.
不要擔心，我不會向其他人說的
Stay with it, Buddy-boy.
待在這裏，小伙子
Who was that?
開始是誰在敲門？
Just somebody delivering a bottle of champagne. Like some?
哦，有人來送香檳！
Would you mind opening that window?
你介意打開窗戶嗎？
- Now don't get any ideas, Miss Kubelik. - I just want some fresh air.
- 庫伯利科小姐，不要有什麼傻念頭 - 我不過想透透氣而已
It's only one storey down. The best you could do is break a leg.
這裏只有一層樓高，你充其量只會摔斷一條腿
So they'll shoot me, like a horse.
他們會痛扁我一頓的
Please, you gotta promise me you won't do anything foolish.
你要答應我你不會做任何的傻事
- Who'd care? - I would.
- 誰會在乎我呢 - 我會
Why can't I ever fall in love with somebody nice like you?
為什麼我沒有愛上你這樣的好人呢？
Yeah. Well ...
好的
That's the way it crumbles, cookiewise.
這是崩潰的好辦法，就像捏碎小甜餅一樣
Go to sleep.
睡一會兒吧
- [women] Good morning, Mr Sheldrake. - Miss Olsen, come into my office, please.
- 早上好，捨爾爵克先生 - 奧爾森小姐，請到我的辦公室來一下
- Did you have a nice Christmas? - Lovely. You were a great help[!]
- 聖誕節過的怎麼樣？ - 托您的福，很不錯
Your pep talk to Miss Kubelik at the office party.
你在公司晚會和庫伯利克小姐說了什麼？
- Sorry, Jeff. I never could hold my liquor. - I thought you could hold your tongue.
- 不好意思，傑夫，我想我可能喝多了 - 我想你應該管好你的嘴
- It won't happen again. - You bet it won't.
- 我保證再也不會這樣了 - 你確實再也不會了
I'll arrange for you to get a month's severance pay.
我會安排給你發一個月工資
That's right, Miss Olsen. I'm letting you go.
好的，奧爾森小姐，我現在放你長假了
You let me go four years ago, Jeff.
傑夫，你四年前就已經拋棄我一次了
And were cruel enough to make me sit out there and watch the new models pass by.
還那麼殘忍讓我坐在外面，看著你一個又一個的新情人來來去去
I'd appreciate it if you'd be out of here as soon as you can.
我希望你能夠馬上從我面前消失
Yes, Mr Sheldrake.
好的，捨爾爵克先生
Operator, this is Mr Sheldrake. I'd like Mr Baxter's home telephone number.
總機，我是捨爾爵克先生，請幫我查一下巴克斯特先生家裏的電話
He's in Ordinary Premium Accounting.
他在普通保險清算部
- [Baxter] Hello? - Hello. Jeff Sheldrake. Can you talk?
喂？喂，傑夫·捨爾爵克，你現在方便講話嗎？
Yes. She's in the shower.
可以，她現在正在洗澡
- She's coming along fine, considering. - Good.
- 現在她一切都還好 - 好的
- Is there anything you need? Money? - No, thank you, Mr Sheldrake.
- 你需要什麼？錢嗎？ - 不用，謝謝，捨爾爵克先生
As a matter of fact, I have some money for you. $100.
事實上，我這裏還有你的100美元
Oh.
噢！
- If there's anything I can do for you ... - For me? I don't think so.
- 這裏還有什麼需要我幫你的嗎？ - 為我？我想不用了
But I was hoping maybe you could do something for her.
但是我真的希望你能為她做一些事情
Like what? Put yourself in my place, Baxter.
比如說呢？巴克斯特，你設身處地的為我想想
How can I help her? My hands are tied.
我現在怎麼能幫她呢？我現在很忙
Well ... at least you can talk to her.
這樣啊，至少你應該和她通通電話
Let me put her on. And please, be gentle.
你等我讓她穿好衣服，請你對她溫柔點
There's a call for you!
電話打給你的
- For me? - Yeah. Mr Sheldrake.
- 給我？ - 是，捨爾爵克先生。
I don't wanna talk to him.
我不想和他說話
I think you should.
我想你應該和他說說
I gotta run down to the grocery anyway. There's nothing left here but frozen pizza.
我要去下面的雜貨店一趟，除了冰凍匹薩我這裏什麼都沒有了
I'll be right back. OK?
我很快就回來，好嗎？
Hello, Jeff.
喂，傑夫
- Yes, I'm all right. - Why did you do it, Fran?
- 我一切都好 - 弗蘭，為什麼做這種傻事呢？
It's so childish, and it never solves anything.
你太孩子氣了，這解決不了任何問題的
I oughta be very angry with you, scaring me that way.
你這個樣子嚇死我了，我都要氣死了
But let's forget the whole thing, pretend it never happened. What do you say?
讓我們忘記這一切，就當沒發生過你覺得怎麼樣？
Fran?
弗蘭？
Are you there, Fran?
弗蘭，你還在嗎？
Of course I'm not here, because the whole thing never happened.
我當然不在這裏，整件事情也沒有發生
I never took those pills, I never loved you, ...
我從來沒有吃過安眠藥，從來沒有愛過你
.. we never even met.
我們從來也沒有相遇
- Isn't that the way you want it, Jeff? - You know I didn't mean it that way.
- 傑夫，這樣你是不是滿意了？ - 你知道我不是這個意思的
You just get well. Do what the nurse says. I mean Baxter.
你好好養身體吧，按照看護的話去做，我是指巴克斯特
I'll see you as soon as I can. Goodbye, Fran.
我會盡快去看你的，再見，弗蘭
Hello, Mrs Sheldrake. This is Miss Olsen.
喂，是捨爾爵剋夫人嗎？我是奧爾森小姐
Fine, thank you. I was wondering if we could have lunch together.
我很好，謝謝，我想我們是不是可以共進午餐
I don't know how important it is, but you might find it educational.
我不知道這件事情有多嚴重，但是你會覺得對你有用的
It concerns your husband.
是關於你丈夫的事情
All right. One o'clock, Longchamps, Madison and 59th.
好的，1點鐘在曼德森餐館，品味廳59號見
Don't worry. I'm on my way.
不要擔心，我馬上就走
Just making a personal call.
只是打一個私人電話
Here's a dime.
這是一毛錢
Going down.
快離開
Oh, Mr Baxter! I'm glad you're here.
哦，巴克斯特先生，你還在這裏
- I was just going to get the passkey. - What for?
- 我還正準備去拿備用鑰匙呢？ - 幹什麼用？
I thought I smelled gas coming from your apartment.
好像你的公寓裏有煤氣味道傳出來
Gas?!
煤氣？！
Miss Kubelik?
庫伯利克小姐！
- You all right? - Sure!
- 你還好嗎？ - 當然
- What's that funny smell? - Gas! Didn't you turn it on?
- 那這煤氣味是怎麼回事？ - 煤氣！你沒有打開嗎？
Yes, to boil water to get the coffee stains out of my dress.
打開了，我想燒水洗掉我衣服上的咖啡漬
- You turned it on but you didn't light it. - Are you supposed to?
- 你把煤氣打開了，但是沒有點火 - 你想幹什麼？
In this house you're supposed to. Hey, what are you doing with that?
在這間房子幹什麼？嘿，你在幹什麼呢？
I was washing my stockings, so I thought I'd wash your socks too.
我在洗我的襪子，於是順便把你的也洗了
- Oh. Thank you. - Very curious. I could only find 3?pair.
- 哦，謝謝！ - 我很好奇，我怎麼只能找到3只襪子？
Things are a little disorganised around here.
我這裏有些亂糟糟的
I'd say. What's a tennis racket doing in the kitchen?
我還想問一下，為什麼你的廚房有一隻網球拍呢
Tennis racket? Oh, I remember. I was cooking myself an Italian dinner.
網球拍？哦，我想起來了，那是我自己做意大利餐的工具
I used it to strain the spaghetti.
我用它來處理意大利麵條
- Why not? - In fact, I'm a pretty good cook.
- 是這樣啊 - 事實上，我是一個很好的廚師
- Only I'm a lousy housekeeper. - Yes, you are.
- 但是在整理家務上面非常糟糕 - 嗯，確實如此
When I was straightening up the couch, I found six hairpins, a lipstick, ...
當我整理沙發的時候，我發現了6個髮夾，一支口紅
.. a pair of false eyelashes and a swizzle stick from the Stork Club.
一對假眼睫毛，還有斯多克俱樂部的雞尾酒調酒棒
It's just that I'm the kind of guy who can't say no.
這只是因為我對任何人都不拒絕的後果
- I don't mean to girls. I mean ... - To someone like Mr Sheldrake.
我不是指對女孩，我的意思是對像捨爾爵克先生一樣的人
- I guess so. - I know so.
- 我猜也是的 - 我知道
- He's a taker. - What?
- 他是一個情場獵手 - 什麼？
Some people take, some people get took.
一些人捕獵，一些人被獵
And they know they're gettin' took and there's nothin' they can do about it.
他們知道他們需要什麼類型的，而且他們並不需要做什麼
I wouldn't say that.
我也不知道該說什麼
What would you like for dinner, huh?
你中午想吃什麼？
Hey. Onion soup, and canned asparagus ...
嗯，洋蔥湯，罐裝的蘆筍
I really should be getting home.
我現在真的要回去了
- My family'li be flipping by now. - You can't leave yet.
- 我家裏人現在肯定都急瘋了 - 你現在還不能離開
The doctor said it takes 48 hours to get that stuff out of your system.
醫生說過需要48個小時，才能把那些東西清除掉
How long does it take to get someone you're stuck on out of your system?
那多久才能把那些纏著你的人甩開呢？
If only they'd invent some kind of pump for that.
除非他們發明一種專門的抽取泵
I know how you feel, Miss Kubelik. You think it's the end of the world. But it's not.
庫伯利克小姐，我知道你的感受，你認為現在是世界末日，但根本不是你所想的那樣
I went through exactly the same thing myself.
我也經歷過一樣糟糕的事情
- You did? - Well, not exactly the same.
- 你也經歷過？ - 是的，當然也不完全一樣
I tried to do it with a gun.
我想用槍來了結我的一生
- Over a girl? - Worse. It was the wife of my best friend.
- 為了一個女孩？ - 更糟糕，是為了我最好朋友的老婆
And I was mad about her. But I knew it was hopeless and I decided to end it all.
但是我卻瘋狂的愛上了她，我知道這是沒有結果的，於是想結束這一切
I went to a pawnshop and I bought a .45 automatic and I drove up to Eden Park ...
我到了一家當鋪並買了一把點45自動步槍，然後開車到伊甸公園
- Do you know Cincinnati? - No, I don't.
- 你知道辛辛那提嗎？ - 不知道
Anyway, I parked the car and I loaded that gun ...
總之，我停好車，把子彈上膛
You read in the papers that people shoot themselves. Believe me, it's not that easy.
你讀過報紙上說的那些飲彈自盡的文章吧！相信我，事情根本沒有那麼的簡單
I mean, how do you do it? Here? Here? Here?
我知道，那你是怎麼做的？這裏？這裏？還是這裏？
- Know where I finally shot myself? - Where?
- 知道我最後開槍打哪個地方嗎？ - 哪裏？
- Here. - In the knee?!
- 這裏 - 在膝蓋上
Yeah! I was sittin' there, tryin' to decide.
是的，我坐在那裏，然後在想如何了結
A cop came up because I was illegally parked.
因為我違章停車，一個警察走過來
I tried to hide the gun under the seat and it went off.
我想把槍藏在椅子後面，結果槍走火了
- That's terrible! - It was a year till I could bend the knee.
- 太恐怖了 - 整整一年我都不能彎曲我的膝蓋
But I got over the girl in three weeks.
但是後來我三個星期就忘記了那個女孩
Still lives in Cincinnati. Has four kids and gained 20 pounds.
她還在辛辛提那有四個小孩，都有20磅重了
Sends me a fruitcake every Christmas.
每個聖誕節還給我送水果蛋糕、
Are you just making this up to make me feel better?
你是不是編出這樣的故事讓我高興啊
Of course not! Here's the fruitcake.
當然不是，你看這還有水果蛋糕呢
- Do you wanna see my knee? - No, thank you.
- 你想看我的膝蓋嗎？ - 不用了，謝謝！
The fellas in the office might get the wrong idea how I found out.
公司的那些傢伙可能會奇怪我是怎麼知道的
Let 'em! Look, I'm gonna cook dinner for us. We'll have fruitcake for dessert.
好了，我來做中餐，水果蛋糕作為飯後的甜點，如何？
You just sit there and rest. You've done enough for today.
你就坐這裏休息就夠了，今天你的運動已經夠多了
- Yes, Nurse. - [Baxter hums opera music]
好的，看護大人
- Can I help you? - I'm lookin' for Miss Kubelik.
- 我能為你做點什麼？ - 我找庫伯利克小姐
- So am I. She didn't report this morning. - She didn't? Who's in charge here?
- 我也是，她今天早上沒有報到上班 - 她沒有嗎？誰是這裏的主管？
That comes under General Office Administration. Mr Dobisch, 21st floor.
她屬於總部下面的行政部，多比奇先生，21樓
Thanks.
謝謝
So I take Sylvia up to the apartment, and guess who he's stashed in the bedroom.
我今天帶塞維利亞去他的公寓，估計她應該在巴克斯特的房間裏.
- Who? - Kubelik.
- 誰？ - 庫伯利克
No kiddin'? Buddy-boy and Kubelik having a little toot?
別開玩笑了，巴德小伙子會和庫伯利克有一腿
Toot? More like a lost weekend. Neither of 'em showed up for work today.
也許吧！一個不好的週末，他們今天好像都沒有上班
AWOL, hm?
擅離職守，對嗎？
What gripes me is they guzzled my champagne ...
尤其讓我不爽的就是，他們還拿走了我的香檳
.. while Sylvia and I wound up at the Guggenheim Museum.
而我和塞爾維亞在高格漢姆博物館凍得要死
- Mr Dobisch? - Yeah.
- 科比奇先生嗎？ - 是的
I'm Karl Matuschka. My sister-in-law runs one of the elevators. Fran Kubelik.
我叫卡爾·馬塔斯奇卡，我的妹妹叫弗蘭·庫伯利克，在你們這裏開電梯
- Miss Kubelik? - You know her?
- 庫伯利克小姐？ - 你認識她嗎？
Of course. We have a lot of employees, but we're one big, happy family.
當然，我們有很多僱員，但我們是一個快樂的幸福大家庭
She lives with us, and my wife's nervous cos Fran hasn't been home for two days.
她和我們住一起，我妻子克斯弗蘭很擔心
That so?
那樣又如何？
So we wondered if somebody here knew what happened to her.
於是我們在想你們這裏是不是有人知道她的去處
I see.
我明白
What do you think, AI? Can we help the man?
你有什麼意見，埃爾？我們需要幫助這傢伙嗎？
Why not? We don't owe Buddy-boy anything.
為什麼不呢？我們又不欠巴德什麼人情
Yeah. What's Buddy-boy done for us lately?
對，何況巴德最近對我們怎麼樣，你也是很清楚的
Who is Buddy-boy?
誰是巴德？
- Are we dressing for dinner? - No. Just come as you are.
- 我們需要穿好衣服來吃飯嗎？ - 不用，你過來就行了
- You're pretty good with that racket. - You should see my backhand.
- 你很會用這球拍 - 你等一下可以看看我反手擊球
Wait till you see me serve the meatballs.
等一下你就可以看到我怎麼處理這些肉丸
- Shall I light the candles? - It's a must, gracious livingwise.
- 我來點蠟燭 - 這將是非常的浪漫、有情調
Meatball
肉丸
- You bought some napkins. - Might as well go all the way.
- 你買了一些餐巾 - 最好能夠保持一致
You know, I used to live like Robinson Crusoe.
你知道的，我曾經像魯賓遜漂流記中男主角那樣生活
Shipwrecked, among eight people.
在八百萬人的倖存者中
And then one day I saw a footprint in the sand ...
有一天我在沙灘上看到了腳印
..and there you were.
發現你也在這裏
It's a wonderful thing, dinner for two.
太讓人興奮了，兩人晚餐
- Do you usually eat alone? - No. Sometimes I eat with Ed Sullivan.
- 你經常一個人吃飯嗎？ - 不，有時候我和愛德·蘇爾文一起吃
Or sometimes Dinah Shore or Perry Como.
有時候是戴娜·什莎或者是佩雷·克莫
The other night it was Mae West. She was much younger then. Cheers.
另外一個晚上是和梅·韋斯特，她很年輕，乾杯
- Cheers. - Know what we're gonna do after dinner?
- 乾杯 - 我們吃完飯有什麼好計劃？
- The dishes. - I mean after that.
- 吃菜嘍 - 我指那之後
- What? - You don't have to if you don't want to.
- 什麼 - 如果你不喜歡的話不要勉強自己
- Oh, I don't? - We're gonna finish the gin game.
- 哦，不會的 - 我們再繼續打牌吧
- So keep a clear head. - [doorbell]
保持清醒的頭腦
Cos I don't wanna take advantage of you, the way I did yesterday in bed.
因為我不想利用你，我昨天在你睡著時候做的事情
- Baxter? - Yes.
- 巴克斯特在嗎？ - 在
What's with you, Fran? Did you forget where you live?
弗蘭，你和誰在一起呢？你不記得你住在哪裏了嗎？
- My brother-in-law, Karl Matuschka. - Oh! How do you do, Mr Matusch ...
- 我姐夫，卡爾·馬塔斯奇卡 - 你好，馬塔斯奇卡先生
- Get dressed. I got the cab downstairs. - Wait. I know what you're thinking, but...
- 快穿好衣服，我車在樓下等你 - 等等，我知道你在想什麼
It's none of my business what you do. You're over 21.
你做什麼不關我的事情，你已經超過21歲了
- But your sister thinks you're a lady. - All we were gonna do was eat!
- 但是你姐姐還認為你是一個小女孩 - 我們只是在這裏吃飯
If there wasn't a lady present, I'd clobber you.
如果不是這裏有一位女士在場的話，我會痛扁你一頓的
All right, Karl! I'll get dressed.
好的，卡爾，我去穿衣服
Want a martini?
來一杯馬提尼如何？
How about some spaghetti with meat sauce that I cooked myself?
來一些我做的意大利肉醬面？
Your sister-in-law sure is terrific.
你姐夫實在太恐怖了
It must be murder drivin' a cab in New York with the cross-town traffic.
如果他在馬路上開車，肯定會害死其他司機的
Hi, Baxter. How's the patient?
嗨，巴克斯特，病人現在情況怎麼樣？
Oh, uh ... I'm fine, Doc.
哦，我還好，醫生
Not you. Miss Kubelik.
不是你，是庫伯利克小姐
- What's the matter with Miss Kubelik? - This is Mr Matuschka. He's ... got a cab.
- 庫伯利克小姐發生什麼事情了？ - 他是馬塔斯奇卡先生，一個出租車司機
- Fran been sick? - No. Just a little accident.
- 弗蘭生病了嗎？ - 沒有，出了一點小意外
- What does he mean, accident? - Well. .. these things happen all the time.
- 他的話是什麼意思，意外？ - 哦，是這樣的，這些事情一直都在發生
What things? What kind of a doctor are you?
什麼事情？你究竟當的什麼醫生？
Not that kind! He just gave her a shot, pumped out her stomach.
不是什麼，他只是給她打了一針，然後洗了一下胃
- What for? - I took sleeping pills. But I'm fine now.
- 為什麼？ - 我吃了安眠藥，不過我現在已經沒事了
- Why'd you take sleeping pills? - On account of me.
- 你為什麼吃安眠藥？ - 因為我
you?
你？
Who else?
能有其他人嗎？
Leave him alone!
放開他
Oh, you fool. You damn fool.
哦，你這個傻瓜，太傻了
- [Karl] Come on, Fran. - Goodbye, Mr Baxter.
- 快走，弗蘭 - 巴克斯特先生，再見
Goodbye, Doctor.
再見，醫生
Well, I don't wanna gloat, but just between us, you had it coming to you.
好了，我不想幸災樂禍，不過你剛才確實很有勇氣承擔責任
You're gonna have a shiner tomorrow.
你明天就會有一個黑眼圈
Let me get my bag.
讓我拿一下包
Don't bother, Doc.
不用擔心，醫生
It doesn't hurt a bit.
傷的不是很厲害
Mr Sheldrake's office? This is CC Baxter.
捨爾爵克先生的辦公室嗎？我是CC·巴克斯特
Please tell him I'd like to come up and see him. It's important.
請告訴他我想現在就見他，有很重要的事情
Will you call me back, please?
請問你能打回來嗎？
Mr Sheldrake, I've got good news for you.
捨爾爵克先生，我有好消息要告訴你
All your troubles are over.
所有的麻煩都結束了
I'm gonna take Miss Kubelik off your hands.
我想我可以幫你擺脫庫伯利克小姐
The plain fact is, I love her.
事實就是我喜歡她
I thought you should be the first to know.
我想你是第一個知道的人
After all, you don't really want her, and I do.
畢竟，你不喜歡她，而我卻喜歡
And though it may sound presumptuous, she needs somebody like me.
雖然這聽起來有些專橫，但是她需要像我這樣的人來照顧
- So I think it would be best all around. - [phone rings]
於是我想我應該是最適合的人選
Solutionwise.
這樣才能解決問題
Yes?
喂？
I'll be right up.
我馬上上來
Mr Sheldrake, I've got good news for you.
捨爾爵克先生，我有好消息要告訴你
All your troubles are over.
所有的麻煩都結束了
19.
19樓
- Hi, Buddy-boy. What happened to you? - Hit by a swinging door?
- 嗨，巴德小伙子，你怎麼了？ - 被門撞到了嗎？
- Or a yellow cab? - That guy really must've belted him.
- 或者是黃色的出租車撞到了 - 那個傢伙可能已經揍了他
Yeah. He's punchy. Talking to himself.
是的，你看他已經心不在焉，自言自語
27.
27樓
Those two days she spent in the apartment...
這兩天她住在我的公寓裏
.. made me realise how lonely I'd been before.
才讓我意識到我原來多麼的孤獨
But, thanks to you, I'm in a financial position to marry her.
但是多虧了你，讓我有足夠的收入來娶她
If I can ever square things with her family.
如果我能和她的家人協商好的話
Good morning. CC Baxter.
早上好，CC·巴克斯特先生
- Mr Baxter is here. - Send him in.
- 他已經到了 - 讓他進來
Mr Sheldrake, I've got good news for you.
捨爾爵克先生，我有好消息要告訴你
And I've got good news for you, Baxter.
巴克斯特，我也有好消息告訴你
- All your troubles are over. - Sir?
所有的問題都迎刃而解了。先生？
I know how worried you were about Miss Kubelik. Stop worrying.
我知道你很擔心庫伯利克小姐，現在你不用管了
I'm going to take her off your hands.
我將要把她從你那裏接過來
- You're gonna take her off my hands? - That's right.
- 從我這裏接過去 - 很對
I've moved out of the house.
我已經從家裏搬出來了
I'm gonna be staying in town, at the Athletic Club.
目前打算住在鎮上，住在運動俱樂部
- You left your wife. - If you must know, I fired my secretary.
- 你和你妻子離婚了？ - 如果你非要知道的話，我告訴你，我炒掉我的秘書
My secretary got to my wife, and my wife fired me. Ain't that a kick in the head?
我秘書告訴了我的妻子，我妻子炒掉我，對我而言真是一個重大的不幸
Yeah.
是的
Now what's your news, Baxter?
巴克斯特，你有什麼好消息可以告訴我的
It's about Miss Kubelik. She's feeling all right again so she went home.
是關於庫伯利克小姐的，她現在完全康復，然後回家去了
Swell. And don't think I've forgotten what you did for me_
很好，我沒有忘記你為我做的事情
This way, Baxter.
這邊來，巴克斯特
Sit down. Try it on for size.
坐下，大小合適嗎？
- You like? It's all yours. - Mine?
- 喜歡嗎？這裏都是你的 - 我的？
My assistant has been shifted to the Denver office and you're taking his place.
我的助理已經被輪調到丹佛的辦公室，由你來接替他的位置
What's the matter? You don't seem very excited.
怎麼了，有什麼事情嗎？你看起來好像並不很興奮
Well, it's just that so many things have been happening so fast.
哦，只是很多事情變化太快了，讓我都有些無所適從
I'm very pleased. Especially for Miss Kubelik.
我很高興，特別為庫伯利克小姐高興
think she's the kind of girl that definitely ought to be married to ... someone.
我覺得她就是那種合適嫁給一些人的女孩
Sure, sure. But first the property has to be settled. Then it takes six weeks in Reno.
當然，當然，首先我要處理好財產問題，然後再花六個星期的時間在雷諾休息。
Meanwhile I'm going to enjoy being a bachelor for a while.
同時我也要好好地享受一下單身漢的快樂
Oh, Baxter, you now can have lunch in the executive dining room.
對了，巴克斯特，你可以在經理餐廳吃飯了
That's one of the privileges that goes with this job.
這是擔任這一工作的特權之一
You also get a nice little expense account, use of the executive washroom ...
你還可以公費報銷一些項目，使用經理盥洗室
Say, what happened to you, Baxter?
嘿，巴克斯特，你怎麼了？
- I got kicked in the head too. - Oh?
- 我也備受打擊 - 哦
Good evening, Mr Baxter.
晚安，巴克斯特先生
Oh.
哦
Miss Kubelik. How are you feeling?
庫伯利克小姐，你現在感覺如何？
- I feel fine. How's your eye? - Oh, fine.
- 我很好，你的眼睛怎麼樣了？ - 哦，沒事
- How are things at the apartment? - Nothing's changed.
- 公寓現在怎麼樣 - 還是老樣子，什麼都沒變
- We never did finish that gin game. - I know.
- 我們那個牌局還沒有打完呢 - 我知道
I suppose you heard about Mr Sheldrake.
我想你已經知道捨爾爵克的事情了吧
Leaving his wife? Yeah. I'm very happy for you.
和他夫人離婚？對，我很為他高興
- I never thought he'd do it. - I told you all along.
- 我從來沒有想過他會做這件事情 - 我早就告訴過你了
- You were wrong about Mr Sheldrake. - I guess so.
- 你對捨爾爵克先生有一些誤會 - 我想是的吧
You were wrong about me too.
你對我也有一些誤會
What you said about those who take and those who get took.
就是關於誰泡誰和誰被泡的問題
Mr Sheldrake wasn't using me. I was using him. See?
捨爾爵克先生沒有利用我，我在玩他，明白嗎？
Last month I was at desk 861 on the 19th floor. Now I'm on the 27th floor.
上個月我在19樓的861號桌子，現在我在27樓了
A panelled office, three windows.
套間的辦公室，還有三扇窗屍
So it all worked out fine. We're both getting what we wanted.
因此一切都發展得很好，我們各得其所
Yes. Will you walk me to the subway?
是的，你能陪我到地鐵嗎？
No, thank you. Well, I ... To tell you the truth, I have this heavy date for tonight.
不了，謝謝，我告訴你，我今天晚上有一個很重要的約會
- Aren't you meeting Mr Sheldrake? - No. You know how people talk.
- 你不和捨爾爵克先生會面嗎？ - 不，你知道人言可畏的
I decided it was best not to see each other until everything was settled, divorcewise.
我決定在所有事情都解決好之前不和他見面，也就是等他離婚之後
That's very wise.
明智之舉
- Good night, Mr Baxter. - Good night.
- 晚安，巴克斯特先生 - 晚安
- Baxter, could you step in here a minute? - Yes, Mr Sheldrake.
- 巴克斯特，你能到我這裏來一下嗎？ - 好的，捨爾爵克先生
- There you are. - Much obliged.
- 這是你要的東西 - 非常感謝
Here are the figures on staff turnover. 37% of females leave to get married and 22% ...
這是員工離職率，為37%，女性員工結婚率為22%...
Baxter, you work too hard. It's New Year's Eve. Relax!
巴克斯特，你工作太辛苦了，今天是除夕，放鬆點
- Yes, sir. - I suppose you'll be celebrating tonight.
- 是的，先生 - 我想你今天晚上應該慶祝一番吧
- Naturally. - I'm taking Miss Kubelik out.
- 那是自然 - 我準備約庫伯利克小姐出來
- I finally talked her into it. - I see.
- 我想和她促膝暢談 - 我明白
The only thing is, I'm staying at the Athletic Club and it's strictly stag, so ...
唯一的問題是我還住在運動俱樂部，那裏全是男的，不太方便
If you don't mind?
如果你不介意的話？
- Don't mind what? - You know my key to your apartment?
- 不介意什麼 - 你知道的，你公寓的鑰匙
When we had that little scare about Miss Kubelik, ...
就是我們被庫伯利克小姐嚇了一跳的地方
- .. I threw it out the window of the train. - Very clever.
- 我早就忘記了 - 非常聰明
So now I'll have to borrow your key.
所以現在我要借用你的鑰匙
- Sorry, Mr Sheldrake. - What do you mean, sorry?
- 不好意思，捨爾爵克先生 - 不好意思，為什麼？
You're not bringing anybody to my apartment.
你不能帶任何人再到我的公寓來
- It's not just anybody. It's Miss Kubelik. - Especially not Miss Kubelik.
- 不是別人，是庫伯利克小姐 - 她更不行
- How's that again? - No key.
- 我再問你一遍？ - 不行
Baxter, I picked you for my team because I thought you were a bright young man.
巴克斯特，我把你調到我身邊是因為我覺得你是一個非常年輕聰明的孩子
Do you realise what you're doing? Not to me, but to yourself?
你知道你在幹什麼嗎？這對我沒什麼，但是對你影響有多大？
Normally it takes years to work your way up to the 27th floor.
一般來說你要花很多時間才能到27樓來工作
But it only takes 30 seconds to be out on the street again.
但是可能只要30秒鐘你就可以被掃地出門
- You dig? - I dig.
- 你懂嗎？ - 我懂
So what's it going to be?
那你現在應該怎麼辦呢？
- Now you're being bright. - Thank you, sir.
- 這樣才對 - 謝謝，先生
- Baxter, you gave me the wrong key. - No, I didn't.
- 巴克斯特，你拿錯鑰匙給我了 - 沒有
But this is the key to the executive washroom.
但這是經理盥洗室的鑰匙
That's right. I won't be needing it because I'm all washed up around here.
沒錯，我不再需要它了，因為我已經要離開這裏
- What's gotten into you? - Just following doctor's orders.
- 你傻了嗎？ - 你要聽我的話
I've decided to become a mensch. Know what that means? A human being.
我想做一個人，知道什麼意思嗎？一個堂堂正正的人
- Now hold on, Baxter. - The old payola won't work any more.
- 等等，巴克斯特 - 這種逢迎拍馬的老伎倆沒用了
Goodbye, Mr Sheldrake.
再見，捨爾爵克先生
- We're having a party and ran out of ice. - Sure, Doc.
- 我們有一個晚會，沒有冰了，你可以拿過來一些嗎？ - 好的，醫生
How come you're alone on New Year's Eve?
在除夕之夜你怎麼一個人呢
Well, I got things to do.
哦，我要做一些事情
- What's this? You're packing? - Yeah. I'm giving up the apartment.
- 這是什麼，你在收拾行李？ - 是的，我準備離開這裏
Where are you moving to?
你要到哪裏發展呢？
I don't know. All I know is I gotta get outta this place.
我不知道，不過有一點可以確認，就是離開這裏
Sorry to lose you, Baxter.
巴克斯特，看到你要走，我很難過
Me? Oh, my body. Don't worry, it'll go to the university, Doc. I'll put it in writing.
我？哦，我的身體，不要擔心，我還會捐給大學的，我在寫申請
- Could you use some champagne? - Booze we don't need.
- 需要香檳嗎？ - 我們不喝酒
Say, why don't you join us?
嘿，為什麼不和我們一起玩呢
We got two brain surgeons, a proctologist and three nurses from Bellevue.
我們有兩個腦外科醫生，一個直腸病學家，三個從貝利弗來的護士
No, thanks. I don't feel like it.
不用，謝謝，我現在沒心情
In case I don't see you again, how much do lowe you for taking care of that girl?
萬一以後我們碰不到面了，我怎麼償還你幫我照顧那個女孩的人情
Forget it. I didn't do it as a doctor. I did it as a neighbour.
不要想了，我沒當自己是醫生，我只是在盡一個鄰居的義務
By the way, whatever happened to her?
順便問一句，她現在怎麼樣了？
You know me with girls. Easy come, easy go.
你知道我和女孩如何談得了！來也匆匆，去也匆匆
- Goodbye, Doc. - Happy New Year.
- 再見，醫生 - 新年快樂
Sorry I took so long on the phone. We're all set.
不好意思，我打了太久的電話，一切都準備好了
- For what? - I rented a car. It'll be here at one.
- 幹什麼？ - 我租了一輛車，我們一點的時候用
- We're driving to Atlantic City. - Atlantic City?
- 我們開車到亞特蘭大 - 亞特蘭大？
I know it's a drag, but you can't find a hotel room in town on New Year's Eve.
我知道太遠了，可是在除夕之夜紐約的酒店根本沒有空房間
Ring out the old year, ring in the new.
辭舊迎新
Ring-a-ding-ding.
我們來狂歡吧！
I didn't plan it this way. It's Baxter's fault.
我也不想這樣的，這都是巴克斯特的錯
Baxter?
巴克斯特？
He wouldn't give me the key to the apartment.
他不願意給我公寓的鑰匙
- He wouldn't? - No. He just walked out on me. Quit.
- 他不願意？ - 是的，他離開我，辭職了
Threw that big, fat job right in my face.
拋棄了在我身邊的這麼好的工作
- The nerve. - The little punk. After all I did for him.
神經病，廢物一個，畢竟他的一切都是我給的
Said I couldn't bring anybody to the apartment, especially not Miss Kubelik.
還說我再也不能帶任何人到他的公寓，特別是庫伯利克小姐不行
What's he got against you, anyway?
那麼他為什麼要和你作對呢？
I don't know. I guess that's the way it crumbles, cookiewise.
我不知道，也許這是最好的解決辦法，就像粉碎的小甜餅一樣
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼
I'd spell it out for you, only I can't spell.
我想為你把它拼出來，可是我不會
[all] Should auld acquaintance be forgot
# Should auld acquaintance be forgot
And never brought to mind ...
# And never brought to mind…
Happy New Year, Fran.
新年快樂，弗蘭
And days of auld lang syne
# And days of auld lang syne
For auld lang syne, my dear
# For auld lang syne, my dear
For auld lang syne
# For auld lang syne
We'll drink a cup of kindness yet
# We'll drink a cup of kindness yet
Fran?
弗蘭？
Where are you, Fran?
你跑哪裏去了，弗蘭？
Mr Baxter!
巴克斯特先生
Mr Baxter! Mr Baxter!
巴克斯特先生！巴克斯特先生
Oh!
天啊！
- Are you all right? - I'm fine.
- 你還好嗎？ - 我很好
Are you sure? How's your knee?
你確認嗎？你膝蓋怎麼樣？
I'm fine all over.
渾身上下都沒有問題
- Mind if I come in? - Of course not.
- 介意我進來嗎？ - 當然不
Let me get another glass.
我給你拿一隻杯子
- Where are you going? - Who knows?
- 你準備去哪裏？ - 天知道
Another neighbourhood, another town, another job.
找另外一個鄰居，到另外一個城市，再找另外一份工作
I'm on my own.
我現在一個人過
That's funny. So am I.
太有趣了，我也是
What'd you do with the cards?
你把牌放哪裏去了？
In there.
在那裏
What about Mr Sheldrake?
那捨爾爵克先生呢
I'm gonna send him a fruitcake every Christmas.
我會每個聖誕節送他一個水果蛋糕
Cut.
切牌
I love you, Miss Kubelik.
我愛你，庫伯利克小姐
Queen.
皇后(Q)
Did you hear what I said, Miss Kubelik? I absolutely adore you.
你聽到我說什麼嗎？庫伯利克小姐，我絕對喜歡你
Shut up and deal.
閉嘴，我們打牌